<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>mindset on Macawls&#39; Blog</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/tags/mindset/</link>
        <description>Recent content in mindset on Macawls&#39; Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://macawls.github.io/blog/tags/mindset/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>What is Limerence? 🧠</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/what-is-limerence/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/what-is-limerence/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/what-is-limerence/thumb.PNG" alt="Featured image of post What is Limerence? 🧠" /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WUu39PJ_TI0&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to undertake therapy recently. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a significant change in my behavior and thoughts as a result of several events occurring in close interim, not necessarily because of a negative mental state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/v1.Y2lkPTc5MGI3NjExYmMxYzA4M2ZkZTg1NWY2YjhhNDE3NmVlZWExZmY1M2M1ZWYzZTBhYiZlcD12MV9pbnRlcm5hbF9naWZzX2dpZklkJmN0PWc/pMtLKNjb2IVXO/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time I&amp;rsquo;d been in therapy was back in highschool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That experience taught me to immediately open-up as a sort of preventative measure of inadvertently remaining in a state of mental rumination, which in everyday conversation means &lt;em&gt;being in your own head&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all it&amp;rsquo;s worth I think thats fairly significant. Key things I&amp;rsquo;ve identified about myself include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being emotionally unavailable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Difficulty comprehending empathy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Putting a shield over my heart in order to protect myself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men are often taught to dismiss, disregard or suppress their emotions as a result of societal expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look up to my dad because he&amp;rsquo;s my superman. He never lets emotions cloud his judgement and I feel that I&amp;rsquo;m on the same path, although he is much more emotionally intelligent than I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I truly believe I have a strong sense of identity, but right now it feels like there&amp;rsquo;s many parts of myself that I selectively show to specific people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;mirror.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;260&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Why?&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do this in an attempt to min/max and allow everything I desire to manifest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;swift.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I delusional? Yes very much so 😎👍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I were to reflect on my past relationships, it seems that whenever I have shown vulnerability, it&amp;rsquo;s often backfired or resulted in negative consequences. As if the more exposed I am, the more I could invite unnecessary harm upon myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/M9mRuGEauiwCtfShtc/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how do we cultivate long lasting quality friendships without vulnerability? How do we nurture them without expressing emotions? That&amp;rsquo;s obviously not possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/ZtB2l3jHiJsFa/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across this term on the path to understanding myself more, called &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Limerence&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Limerence&lt;/a&gt; . I went on sort of a spiral with this term and it really intrigued me. From this point onwards the post will be less personal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-limerence&#34;&gt;What is Limerence?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;limerence&amp;rdquo; was coined by psychologist Dorothy Tennov in her book &amp;ldquo;Love and Limerence: The Experience of Being in Love,&amp;rdquo; which was first published in 1979. That was about four decades ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the term itself may not be widely known outside of psychology, the experiences and behaviors associated with limerence have been observed and discussed for a really long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limerence has been acknowledged as a psychological phenomenon and has garnered attention in the study of romantic relationships and attachment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a mental state characterized by infatuation, often in a romantic/sexual context. It involves being deeply captivated by someone, fixating on them, and experiencing strong yearning and longing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, limerence revolves around an idealized version of the person, crafted within one&amp;rsquo;s mind, rather than a true representation of who they are. This captivating state is involuntary, and individuals affected by limerence cannot easily control or choose their feelings towards the person of their infatuation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;rainbow.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life&amp;rsquo;s unpredictable nature never fails to astonish me. None of us truly know anything for sure, it&amp;rsquo;s as if we&amp;rsquo;re all blindly following one another. You would think that we have a choice on what intrigues us or the freedom to choose what we find captivating. Like the preconceived notion of what we supposedly find attractive is absolute when in reality that&amp;rsquo;s far from the truth. It&amp;rsquo;s all an illusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will return to limerence, for now I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to explore the definition of addiction since the two phenomena share some similarities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-addiction&#34;&gt;Understanding Addiction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
Our mind easily tricks us into thinking we&#39;re in control.
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/1L5YuA6wpKkNO/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, it may seem like we have a say in whether or not we engage in addictive behaviors. We might convince ourselves that we can stop at any time or that we have the willpower to resist temptation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
We might go on to say, &lt;i&gt;&#34;Oh yeah I can stop this thing for three weeks&#34;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a deeper level, the three weeks was always accomplishable, reinforcing the illusion that we&amp;rsquo;re in control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Delulu 🤪🤟
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not an arbitrary duration, it came from somewhere. The truth is that these self-imposed limits are meant to maintain the illusion of control rather than challenging the addictive patterns. Addiction operates on a deeper level, beyond the realm of conscious willpower. The cravings and ingrained patterns of behavior will persist, waiting for an opportunity to resurface and overpower our self-control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;doggo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;i&gt;The sense of enlightenment is evident in [Figure 5], as this astute canine intently reads my post and makes a connection between its behavior and its owner&#39;s treats&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behaviors that trigger addictive responses activate the brain&amp;rsquo;s reward pathway, flooding it with dopamine. This flood of pleasure reinforces the desire to repeat the behavior, leading to a cycle of craving, indulgence, and temporary relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To truly grasp addiction, we need to recognize its complexities and understand that it&amp;rsquo;s not just about willpower or making choices. It&amp;rsquo;s a complicated condition that messes with our reward systems, our thoughts and behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/xT1R9LUBYOXB4b8E6Y/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To digress a little bit, &amp;lsquo;Chocolate boy&amp;rsquo; was a character in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hey_Arnold!&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hey Arnold&lt;/a&gt; that was a metaphor for substance abuse/addiction that aired on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nickelodeon&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Nickelodeon&lt;/a&gt;. Thought this was interesting to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gYWYINshEag&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty dark for a children&amp;rsquo;s show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-link-between-addiction-and-limerence&#34;&gt;The Link Between Addiction and Limerence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While limerence is not synonymous with addiction, there are notable connections between the two that I&amp;rsquo;ll explore in the subtopics below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/lXu72d4iKwqek/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I dive into this section, I think its important to understand that limerence is not a bad thing. It&amp;rsquo;s a natural phenomenon completely out of our control. However, it can be harmful if we can&amp;rsquo;t recognize or comprehend the extent of its effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;similar-neurochemical-processes&#34;&gt;Similar Neurochemical Processes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both experiences involve the release of dopamine. In addiction, substances or behaviors trigger dopamine release, reinforcing the desire to repeat the behavior. Similarly, during limerence, the presence or even the mere thought of the desired person can stimulate dopamine release, stimulating pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/38tjCITcNUmWc/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;330&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;obsessive-nature-and-compulsive-behavior&#34;&gt;Obsessive Nature and Compulsive Behavior&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limerence often manifests as an obsessive preoccupation. Individuals experiencing limerence may engage in repetitive thoughts, daydreaming, and fantasizing about the desired person. This nature bears resemblance to the compulsive behaviors observed in addiction. Both limerence and addiction can drive individuals to engage in repetitive and sometimes harmful actions, even against logical judgement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/3o7aDdyo3zIa5aJKG4/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;320&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;escapism-and-emotional-dependence&#34;&gt;Escapism and Emotional Dependence&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both addiction and limerence can serve as forms of escapism or emotional coping mechanisms. People may turn to addictive substances or behaviors, as well as limerent fantasies, to escape from reality, numb emotional pain, or find solace. In both cases, the underlying motivation often stems from a desire to fulfill unmet emotional needs or seek temporary relief from psychological distress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/xT0Gqu0s3j4auj4QP6/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;280&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;interference-with-daily-functioning&#34;&gt;Interference with Daily Functioning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Addiction and limerence can significantly impact daily functioning and overall well-being. Both can consume a person&amp;rsquo;s thoughts, making it challenging to focus on other aspects of life. The pursuit of the addictive substance or the limerent person can overshadow responsibilities, relationships, and personal goals, leading to disruptions in various areas of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/vWye6xPB61oZ7Mx8hq/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;320&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-difference-between-love-and-limerence&#34;&gt;The Difference between Love and Limerence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s a necessity for me to explain what love is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distinction between love and limerence is often a source of confusion. They&amp;rsquo;re sort of a union. Both involve intense feelings for another person but there are important differences to consider. Whats even more confusing is,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limerence can evolve into love over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love can evolve into limerence over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love and limerence can coexist or evolve over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making it even more difficult to distinguish between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/RsovLXVXN8BKo/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, in the early stages of a romantic relationship, limerence may be more prevalent, while love develops and deepens over time as the relationship matures. In rare cases, limerence may even develop in the context of an existing long-term relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-differences&#34;&gt;Key Differences&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limerence is often accompanied by feelings of anxiety and uncertainty, whereas love is secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is a deep affection and attachment to someone that has stood the test of time, whereas limerence is typically a short-lived infatuation with someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limerence is a state of mind that can be triggered by a romantic interest, whereas love is a stable commitment to someone regardless of whether or not the person is reciprocating feelings of affection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limerence is often characterized by obsessive thoughts and fantasies about the desired person, whereas love is more grounded in reality and involves a deeper, more unconditional acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;evolutionary-perspective-on-limerence&#34;&gt;Evolutionary Perspective on Limerence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reproduction is a fundamental part of human nature. It&amp;rsquo;s a biological imperative that has been ingrained in our DNA through millions of years of evolution. The drive for limerence is a byproduct of this evolutionary process and it&amp;rsquo;s almost always associated with lust, romantic or sexual desire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;bra.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
Why? 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put simply, its a mechanism that helps us find a suitable mate and increase the likelihood of survival for our offspring. The heightened state of arousal and infatuation limerence induces leads people to engage in behaviors that are conducive to attracting and maintaining a romantic partner, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efforts in courtship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Displays of affection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emotional bonding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modern-day-implications-of-limerence-in-relationships&#34;&gt;Modern Day Implications of Limerence in Relationships&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While limerence may have evolved as an adaptive mechanism for mate selection specifically, it is not the sole determinant of successful long-term relationships. Factors such as compatibility, shared values, communication styles, emotional connection and commitment also play significant roles in the formation and maintenance of relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limerence can sometimes be so powerful that it can overshadow these factors and possibly lead to an imbalanced and unsustainable relationship dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-off&#34;&gt;Ending Off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed writing this post, was a fun topic to explore.
I think its important to understand the science behind limerence and how it affects our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no idea that a term for this phenomena even existed. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are many people out there who are experiencing this and don&amp;rsquo;t know what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed reading it as much as I enjoyed writing it. It seems like most of my non-technical posts are leaning into the psychology side of things and I&amp;rsquo;m all for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;duck.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have an amazing day ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The future of this blog</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/the-future-of-this-blog/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/the-future-of-this-blog/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/the-future-of-this-blog/pc.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The future of this blog" /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CPkkgLoZTzY&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is gonna sound poetic as fuck but my blog was supposed to be space where I could unearth the depths of my being. Typing on the keyboard was supposed to capture the sensation of reaching into the darkest parts of my psyche that never made it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, writing provides a similar healing energy to dancing, with the added benefit of being able to revisit my past thoughts. In short, this supposed to be was my sanctuary, my haven, my refuge, exactly how I described it back in December of 2021 on my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/about/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;About Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire point of the blog was to be a free space for myself where I could write about whatever I want, whenever I want, without any restrictions. I&amp;rsquo;ve realized the more people I share this blog with, the trickier it becomes to write about things. In the early days, back when it just was me, myself and I, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have this blog deployed and a domain setup yet, I felt completely free and my creative juices were absolutely fuming. I entered the flow state when writing with barely any effort. I would &lt;em&gt;reeeealllly&lt;/em&gt;  like that back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s frustrating about the brainstorming process for blog post ideas is, I can&amp;rsquo;t exactly be completely transparent.
I brainstorm as much as I did at the start of the blog back in 2021, but don&amp;rsquo;t write posts as frequently as I did back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blog is entirely publicly accessible. If I give the blog to my colleagues it introduces a restriction whereby I can&amp;rsquo;t write about things that are &amp;ldquo;inappropriate&amp;rdquo; for a work environment. If I give it to my friends or family I cannot mention people or experiences that are too personal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I need to be careful about what I write about. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t the initial purpose of my blog. It has most definitely lost its purpose over time. All of the content on the blog will remain the same and I won&amp;rsquo;t be deleting any posts. However, the blog will now be a place where I&amp;rsquo;ll only share things that I&amp;rsquo;m completely comfortable with sharing publicly, so it&amp;rsquo;ll become a lot less personal. I&amp;rsquo;ll still be writing about things that I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about and interested in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Alienation</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/alienation/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/alienation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/v1OKSxN.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Alienation" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro---context&#34;&gt;Intro - Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an insane amount of freedom and agency these days.
I go to campus/classes whenever I like.
My parents pretty much allow me to do &lt;strong&gt;anything I want&lt;/strong&gt; because they trust me, I&amp;rsquo;m responsible and I don&amp;rsquo;t do dumb shit.
With my car(absolutely blessed), I can literally go wherever I want or need. Whats weird is that, I&amp;rsquo;ve been going out less often than before.
Something has me feeling off recently&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-ive-been-feeling&#34;&gt;How I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year was my first year of university and it was great. I was settling in, met a bunch of new people and it was generally pretty exciting throughout. I had a great balance of work and social life. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have as much agency as I do now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling a &lt;strong&gt;huge&lt;/strong&gt; social disconnect.
At the same time, I&amp;rsquo;ve been excelling in my aspirations and school work, &lt;strong&gt;far more&lt;/strong&gt; than I did last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, thats great right? On the other hand, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the close relationships I had last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I do accomplish something I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of, its kinda important for me to recieve some kind of feedback or just idk, something yknow? I feel like the more I progress the more people seem to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go out fairly often and it&amp;rsquo;s not like I don&amp;rsquo;t have friends around. But when I do, whether its going out clubbing or chilling at a friends place, I go because I feel like its important to be &lt;strong&gt;included&lt;/strong&gt;.
I know that I won&amp;rsquo;t be studying forever so I have this fear deep down that I&amp;rsquo;ll miss out on social experiences.
I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy hanging out as much as I used to anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I literally do not care about anyone, which is such a shitty thing to say, but I genuinely feel like this.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m constantly surrounded by so many people I could reach out and talk to, but I don&amp;rsquo;t. I just do not care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People around me are constantly talking about this new food place, or this new club, or this new game, or this new movie, or this person on instagram or whatever and it&amp;rsquo;s so difficult to participate because the conversation doesn&amp;rsquo;t really engage me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I do talk about the things I&amp;rsquo;m personally interested in, which is technology and psychology topics, I feel like a buzzkill. I have quite controversial opinions and hot takes on topics that &lt;strong&gt;many&lt;/strong&gt; people disagree with or struggle to comprehend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, when I do talk about things that interest me, I talk sooooo much and can never summarize it from a high level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I feel like I can never just be honest and be myself. Obviously I do not want to offend anyone, that&amp;rsquo;s the last thing I&amp;rsquo;d want to do. Maybe its a self-confidence/fear issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;life-goals&#34;&gt;Life Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I respect very few of my peers. The only people I &lt;strong&gt;respect&lt;/strong&gt;, are people that are driven and constantly working on extra things, which in my university(rich kids) is incredibly rare to be honest. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what it is, could be work, could be health, could be hobbies, as long as its &lt;strong&gt;something&lt;/strong&gt; they&amp;rsquo;re pushing towards and improving upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like its slowly killing me from the inside. Everyone else seems so&amp;hellip; relaxed. Like there&amp;rsquo;s just no care in the world. I put so much pressure on myself to the point where it&amp;rsquo;s detrimental. I feel like I can&amp;rsquo;t relate to anyone anymore. Perhaps I feel like this because I&amp;rsquo;ve been isolating for so long. I feel like there&amp;rsquo;s just&amp;hellip;. something deep down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clarifications&#34;&gt;Clarifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanna emphasize that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;above&amp;rdquo; others in any way. I&amp;rsquo;m not self-absorbed or yearning for social acceptance. I just, suddenly feel a massive disconnect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/MjXPTqy.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Taoism and Rastafarianism</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/420.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Taoism and Rastafarianism" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I want to emphasize that what I am about to say is highly subjective and is part of my personal interpretation.
I decided to write this because I find both fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;their-origins&#34;&gt;Their Origins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For context sake, Taoism has been around for a really long time; since around the 4th century, and started in China. Rastafarianism actually started as a political movement in the 1930s in Jamaica and emerged from the &lt;strong&gt;Abrahamic&lt;/strong&gt; religions, namely Christianity and Judaism and as such, is monotheistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also where the stark contrast between the two lies. The key word is movement. Rastafarianism never emerged solely because of religious values, but it is still essential and grounded in the movement. Taoism was purely philosophical, devoid of any politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-definition-of-religion&#34;&gt;The definition of Religion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Religion is a difficult word to define. I personally believe both these belief systems can be defined rather as a &amp;ldquo;Way of Life&amp;rdquo; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that when a &amp;lsquo;religion&amp;rsquo; has more strict beliefs, is unified and becomes widely institutionalized, it falls under the &amp;lsquo;religion&amp;rsquo; category. Example&amp;rsquo;s would be Christianity, Hinduism, Islam including their many respective forms and so on. However, that&amp;rsquo;s not to say places of worship for Taoism and Rastafarianism do not exist, because they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Taoism and Rastafari Culture embrace the idea of treading on your &lt;strong&gt;own&lt;/strong&gt; path to enlightenment, finding peace and content in life&amp;rsquo;s simple joys . Albeit in Rastafarianism it is much more of a collective effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/lol.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1200&#34;
	height=&#34;756&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/lol_hu6db0bf348c7f7ee1fb81ffaed16baf19_381117_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/lol_hu6db0bf348c7f7ee1fb81ffaed16baf19_381117_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;158&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;380px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nature-and-lifestyle&#34;&gt;Nature and Lifestyle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both beliefs, there is a lot of importance placed upon living in harmony and peace with nature.
It is by far the most &lt;strong&gt;crucial&lt;/strong&gt; aspect of both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that often in our day to day lives, we search for meaning and substance in material things.
We consume content, turn to the arts like literature and music, buy things we need or might not that serve some kind of purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end its all kinda just pointless depending on how you view it, at least it is for me.
When you stop for a second, take everything in and find peace and content by simply feeling and existing, that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/chillcat.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;500&#34;
	height=&#34;287&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/chillcat_hu496ab323a84514f468bbad3572766ea9_35475_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/chillcat_hu496ab323a84514f468bbad3572766ea9_35475_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;174&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;418px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How often, do you kinda just forget you have ownership of something? Or how often that one song or show you enjoyed eventually just slips out of your mind? The lessons and experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my life will never leave me. It feels much closer to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;diet&#34;&gt;Diet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rastas are primarily vegan. Their diet is called &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ital&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. They do this because it is believed that a diet free of additives, chemicals and meat is neccessary in order to stay healthy and more spiritually connected to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tao believe the same essentially; eating as close to natural as possible including little meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both discourage the consumption of substances such as nicotine and alcohol as well as other drugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both look down on political systems, violence and authoritarianism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to be vegetarian for around 4 months. Not because of the influences of any religion, mainly animal cruelty and because I honestly feel like humanity is a plague to the earth. Consuming meat is not a necessity by any pragmatical means.  Unfortunately I lost a significant amount of weight and it was quite difficult to have a diet different from my family&amp;rsquo;s without personal income. I plan on continuing once I am self-independent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-off&#34;&gt;Ending off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily &lt;em&gt;follow&lt;/em&gt; Taoism or Rastafarianism. There are aspects are disagree upon in both, more so in Rastafari Culture because of its misogynistic views.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>An Explanation on Ocean&#39;s 47</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/steez.jpg" alt="Featured image of post An Explanation on Ocean&#39;s 47" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The man above is Courtney Jamal Dewar Jr, more commonly known as &lt;strong&gt;Capital Steez&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-capital-steez&#34;&gt;Who is Capital Steez?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital Steez &lt;strong&gt;was&lt;/strong&gt;. He was a rapper from Brooklyn, New York.
He was part of the colletive group; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pro_Era&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pro Era&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro Era or rather the Progressive Era, started out as just a group of friends in highschool, including my favourite rapper, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joey_Badass&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Joey Bada$$&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;capital-steez---apex&#34;&gt;Capital Steez - Apex&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/huISHVRUPUA&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanation&#34;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into detail about Steez&amp;rsquo;s life.
He was Joey&amp;rsquo;s best friend and unfortunately committed suicide on the 23rd of December 2012.
The numbers on date on his death &lt;code&gt;12/23/12&lt;/code&gt; add up to 47.
His last message was &amp;ldquo;THE END&amp;rdquo;.
The next album in his career was going to be called &amp;ldquo;47 Shift&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;long-live-steelo-edit&#34;&gt;Long live Steelo Edit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U-RA22CIvpk&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just simply going to explain &amp;ldquo;Ocean&amp;rsquo;s 47&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to break it up into three parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number &lt;strong&gt;47&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The word &lt;strong&gt;Ocean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Links to &lt;strong&gt;Taoism / Daoism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oceans 47&amp;rdquo; is a line from the track &amp;ldquo;Ring the Alarm&amp;rdquo; by Joey Bada$$, Meechy Darko, Kirk Knight and Nyck Caution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;#34;Death before dishonor, I die for brethren
This is a stick-up, ocean&amp;#39;s 47
Ring the alarm...&amp;#34;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-number-47&#34;&gt;The Number 47&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steez was a leader. He told his peers to do something meaningful with their lives and they followed.
The number 47 would mean nothing to Pro Era without Steez.
Steez saw the number 47 as the perfect number. It is a prime number. The number 4, represents the 4th or &lt;strong&gt;Heart&lt;/strong&gt; Chakra. The number 7, represents the 7th or &lt;strong&gt;Crown&lt;/strong&gt; Chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Steez, its the balance of the heart and mind. The balance of logical and irrational thinking. He believed that when connecting with others, you need to be sympathetic and caring while also not being completely heartless and logical. Now there&amp;rsquo;s also the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.masonic-lodge-of-education.com/47th-problem-of-euclid.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;47th problem of Euclid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, more commonly known as the &lt;strong&gt;Pythagorean&lt;/strong&gt; theorem. There&amp;rsquo;s also connections with the number 47 and the &lt;strong&gt;Swastika&lt;/strong&gt; symbol. There is &lt;strong&gt;also&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;angel numbers&amp;rdquo; and many more stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unrelated to the &lt;strong&gt;number itself&lt;/strong&gt;, is the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://faculty.fiu.edu/~harrisk/Notes/Aesthetics/Apollonian-%20Dionysian%20Dichotomy.htm&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Apollonian&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dionysian&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - directly opposing (however not antithetical) sides of Greek Culture which Friedrich Nietzsche mentioned in his work, &amp;lsquo;The Birth of Tragedy&amp;rsquo;. These dualistic and opposing &amp;lsquo;forces&amp;rsquo; are represented by the two Greek Gods; Apollo and Dionysus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apollo represents reason, rationality, calm and fortitude.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dionysus represents impulse, emotion, instinct and chaos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In simplification, Nietzsche asserted that to be content with oneself is to control the balance of these two forces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ArsS6sPhwn0&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe there is anything significant about the number and it&amp;rsquo;s various connections really. It&amp;rsquo;s about what it represents to me.
Steez&amp;rsquo;s music was highly influential and had left a mark on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do believe that there needs to be a balance between the heart and mind. The number 47 represents this to me.
I think too rationally at times; to the point where I can&amp;rsquo;t connect with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-word-ocean&#34;&gt;The Word Ocean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;lyrics&lt;/strong&gt; of the song, &amp;ldquo;Ocean&amp;rdquo; was simply a reference to the movie &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0240772/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Oceans Eleven&amp;rdquo; (2001)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, it has a different meaning. When I think of an ocean, I think of water endlessly flowing and never resting. Waves crashing. From afar, it is still. On the shore, it exerts its tremendous kinetic energy on the surrounding area. In another blog I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about my trip to Japan, but it also reminds me of the Great Wave of Hokusai for this reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great-wave-of-hokusai&#34;&gt;The Great Wave of Hokusai&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/hokusai.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;800&#34;
	height=&#34;538&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/hokusai_hu12a289ef2460acfe1fa9dc9569991029_168910_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/hokusai_hu12a289ef2460acfe1fa9dc9569991029_168910_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Great Wave Off Kanagawa | Japanese: 神奈川沖浪裏&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;148&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;356px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wave dominates the composition, emphasizing its relative size in comparison to Mount Fuji behind it and the men that are rowing for their lives.
Its destructive when energetic, yet friendly and welcoming when its not.
In a similar fashion, I feel that when people are calm and collected, they are more approachable.
More present.
Their calming and understanding essence feels soothing and even &lt;em&gt;medicinal&lt;/em&gt;.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to be this kind of person to the people I care most about, while also not being completely rational and lacking empathy in some respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, I feel the word Ocean is strongly linked to the number 47. I don&amp;rsquo;t think lyrics necessarily have to have a single-defined meaning. Its fine to interpret them in your own way as you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;taosim&#34;&gt;Taosim&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/tao.png&#34;
	width=&#34;300&#34;
	height=&#34;300&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/tao_hu2ae312aa34be84bde18807b30339ef60_66252_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/tao_hu2ae312aa34be84bde18807b30339ef60_66252_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember back in highschool, we were tasked with researching a religion of our choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t even think Taoism is a &lt;em&gt;religion&lt;/em&gt; per say. Its more like a philosophy or a way of life.
Basically it focuses on a balanced way of living life. Living life in harmony and with nature.
Importantly, in Taoism, opposites rely on each other to coexist.
This is the &lt;em&gt;only religion&lt;/em&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever come across in my life that is the most sensible and agreeable for me personally.
In this way, its linked to the dualistic behaviour of the &lt;strong&gt;ocean&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;balance of chakras&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favourite quotes from Lao Tzu, the founding philosopher of Taoism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;When people see things as beautiful, ugliness is created. ~ Lao Tzu
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-off&#34;&gt;Ending Off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoyed this short read. TLDR: I believe that having a balance in life is important.
I highly recommend to check out some of Capital Steez&amp;rsquo;s music if enjoy you &amp;lsquo;Boom-Bap&amp;rsquo; as a subgenre or just rap in general.
Peace &amp;lt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/cutecat.png&#34;
	width=&#34;480&#34;
	height=&#34;360&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/cutecat_hu7fa53c326e10933a05760b6587936164_215111_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/cutecat_hu7fa53c326e10933a05760b6587936164_215111_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
