<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>mindset on Macawls&#39; Blog</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/tags/mindset/</link>
        <description>Recent content in mindset on Macawls&#39; Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://macawls.github.io/blog/tags/mindset/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Music and 21 Savage</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/music-and-21-savage/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/music-and-21-savage/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/music-and-21-savage/thumb.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Music and 21 Savage" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been expanding my music taste recently. Music is extremely important to me ❤️
&lt;br&gt;
If the melodies are not hitting my soul I don&amp;rsquo;t want it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;doggo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few experiences recently that I believe has shaped me quite a bit. Learnt a lot of lessons.
These include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Believe in yourself over everything else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience new things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Question everything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You cannot predict anything&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never listened to music as much as I did at this point of my life before. In a normal day, I easily hit 2 hours of listening as a minimum. Not simply just one genre, it ranges from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rap (Trap/Boom-Bap)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Melancholic sounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Euphoric, percussion heavy melodic tracks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slow, meditative downtempo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Energetic techno/core&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like with this selection, I get the range of emotions that I want, depending on the time of day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;range.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, what I&amp;rsquo;m getting to is, in this &amp;rsquo;expansion&amp;rsquo;, there&amp;rsquo;s one artist that just makes me feel a different kind of way. The man himself, &lt;strong&gt;21 Savage&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;savage-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-history-with-rap-music&#34;&gt;My history with Rap Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve listened to plenty artists and genres within rap in general but I&amp;rsquo;m going to touch on what I think is most memorable to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I were to go all the way back, boom-bap was my entrypoint which is why the relatively &amp;lsquo;modern&amp;rsquo; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1999_%28mixtape%29&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;1999 by Joey Bada$$&lt;/a&gt; is still my favourite album of all time. I loved the complex storytelling aspect of boom bap. It felt like every single song just had so many layers that you would slowly peel back. Simply 10 listening sessions was not enough. You could go back after a few months and you might be able to connect the dots differently or find hidden meanings that weren&amp;rsquo;t exactly as apparent as before. Figuring out those triple entendres made you feel like an absolute genius. State of Mind by Nas is a classic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hI8A14Qcv68&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it sort of feels like I can&amp;rsquo;t relate because it comes from a time that was just so long ago. Feels more like old history. I guess the lyrics aren&amp;rsquo;t hitting me as hard nowadays. Its quite difficult to describe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;21-savage&#34;&gt;21 Savage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to think trap rap was &amp;lsquo;corny&amp;rsquo; a long time ago because it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as complex lyrically. Like they were just trying to sound &amp;lsquo;cool&amp;rsquo; by saying &amp;lsquo;bad&amp;rsquo; things. Thought I was some kind of &amp;lsquo;intellectual&amp;rsquo; by caring about &amp;lsquo;real rap&amp;rsquo; because it was more poetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;deranged.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300px&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just gonna preface for anyone that might feel offended, especially religiously, this is my opinion. Feel free to disagree. I will try and sound like I&amp;rsquo;m not a bad person 😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize now that I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t relate at all when I was younger and more naive. Life is everything. &amp;lsquo;Bad&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Good&amp;rsquo; if you wanna call it that. We all have this dark, villainous side deep down. Not necessarily &amp;rsquo;emo&amp;rsquo; or sad. We try and hide it to play the game of life. Its important we embrace that energy(within reason obviously) because like other energies, its powerful and moving. We&amp;rsquo;re built for survival, along with kindness and humanity, these are contrasting energies. Certain circumstances bring out different sides of you. Pain and struggle is one of the best teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kind of thinking of getting a padlock on my neck for this reason and more but maybe thats a bit too intense for now 😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s two ways I believe you can reminisce about a &amp;lsquo;bad experience&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This thing happened to me in the past, therefore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a part of me, I can be sad about it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a part of me, it makes me stronger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The absolute energy savage gives me man. He makes me feel like a monster. The second the beat drops, my body&amp;rsquo;s already moving. He makes me feel like, all the bad things I&amp;rsquo;ve done, all of the mistakes and all of the hard times I&amp;rsquo;ve been through doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter in the slightest. You need hardship. Things that take you to the edge and make you a beast. It&amp;rsquo;s all part of the path to growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like everything can be yours to take if you have the grit and resolve 🔪🩸&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His music is insanely inspirational. It feels too real. He&amp;rsquo;s been through so much, more than you would believe. Despite the dark sounds and horrific nature of some of the lyrics, he&amp;rsquo;s crafted a persona built by the terrible times of his past that millions of people can get behind, including myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-off&#34;&gt;Ending Off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed the short read.
I would have liked to share my favourite songs and more information, but I&amp;rsquo;m afraid its far too explicit to post unfortunately. Hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ve added an interesting perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The future of this blog</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/the-future-of-this-blog/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/the-future-of-this-blog/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/the-future-of-this-blog/pc.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The future of this blog" /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CPkkgLoZTzY&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is gonna sound poetic as fuck but my blog was supposed to be space where I could unearth the depths of my being. Typing on the keyboard was supposed to capture the sensation of reaching into the darkest parts of my psyche that never made it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, writing provides a similar healing energy to dancing, with the added benefit of being able to revisit my past thoughts. In short, this supposed to be was my sanctuary, my haven, my refuge, exactly how I described it back in December of 2021 on my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/about/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;About Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire point of the blog was to be a free space for myself where I could write about whatever I want, whenever I want, without any restrictions. I&amp;rsquo;ve realized the more people I share this blog with, the trickier it becomes to write about things. In the early days, back when it just was me, myself and I, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have this blog deployed and a domain setup yet, I felt completely free and my creative juices were absolutely fuming. I entered the flow state when writing with barely any effort. I would &lt;em&gt;reeeealllly&lt;/em&gt;  like that back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s frustrating about the brainstorming process for blog post ideas is, I can&amp;rsquo;t exactly be completely transparent. I had a few amazing experiences in the past 2 months. What&amp;rsquo;s terrible is, I brainstorm as much as I did at the start of the blog back in 2021, but don&amp;rsquo;t write posts as frequently as I did back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blog is entirely publicly accessible. If I give the blog to my colleagues it introduces a restriction whereby I can&amp;rsquo;t write about things that are &amp;ldquo;inappropriate&amp;rdquo; for a work environment. If I give it to my friends or family I cannot mention people or experiences that are too personal. I enjoy my privacy and I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of oversharing. See where I&amp;rsquo;m going with this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I need to be careful about what I write about. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t the initial purpose of my blog. It has most definitely lost its purpose over time. All of the content on the blog will remain the same and I won&amp;rsquo;t be deleting any posts. However, the blog will now be a place where I&amp;rsquo;ll only share things that I&amp;rsquo;m completely comfortable with sharing publicly, so it&amp;rsquo;ll become a lot less personal. I&amp;rsquo;ll still be writing about things that I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about and interested in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Alienation</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/alienation/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/alienation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/v1OKSxN.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Alienation" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro---context&#34;&gt;Intro - Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an insane amount of freedom and agency these days.
I go to campus/classes whenever I like.
My parents pretty much allow me to do &lt;strong&gt;anything I want&lt;/strong&gt; because they trust me, I&amp;rsquo;m responsible and I don&amp;rsquo;t do dumb shit.
With my car(absolutely blessed), I can literally go wherever I want or need. Whats weird is that, I&amp;rsquo;ve been going out less often than before.
Something has me feeling off recently&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-ive-been-feeling&#34;&gt;How I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year was my first year of university and it was great. I was settling in, met a bunch of new people and it was generally pretty exciting throughout. I had a great balance of work and social life. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have as much agency as I do now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling a &lt;strong&gt;huge&lt;/strong&gt; social disconnect.
At the same time, I&amp;rsquo;ve been excelling in my aspirations and school work, &lt;strong&gt;far more&lt;/strong&gt; than I did last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, thats great right? On the other hand, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the close relationships I had last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I do accomplish something I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of, its kinda important for me to recieve some kind of feedback or just idk, something yknow? I feel like the more I progress the more people seem to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go out fairly often and it&amp;rsquo;s not like I don&amp;rsquo;t have friends around. But when I do, whether its going out clubbing or chilling at a friends place, I go because I feel like its important to be &lt;strong&gt;included&lt;/strong&gt;.
I know that I won&amp;rsquo;t be studying forever so I have this fear deep down that I&amp;rsquo;ll miss out on social experiences.
I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy hanging out as much as I used to anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I literally do not care about anyone, which is such a shitty thing to say, but I genuinely feel like this.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m constantly surrounded by so many people I could reach out and talk to, but I don&amp;rsquo;t. I just do not care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People around me are constantly talking about this new food place, or this new club, or this new game, or this new movie, or this person on instagram or whatever and it&amp;rsquo;s so difficult to participate because the conversation doesn&amp;rsquo;t really engage me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I do talk about the things I&amp;rsquo;m personally interested in, which is technology and psychology topics, I feel like a buzzkill. I have quite controversial opinions and hot takes on topics that &lt;strong&gt;many&lt;/strong&gt; people disagree with or struggle to comprehend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, when I do talk about things that interest me, I talk sooooo much and can never summarize it from a high level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I feel like I can never just be honest and be myself. Obviously I do not want to offend anyone, that&amp;rsquo;s the last thing I&amp;rsquo;d want to do. Maybe its a self-confidence/fear issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;life-goals&#34;&gt;Life Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I respect very few of my peers. The only people I &lt;strong&gt;respect&lt;/strong&gt;, are people that are driven and constantly working on extra things, which in my university(rich kids) is incredibly rare to be honest. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what it is, could be work, could be health, could be hobbies, as long as its &lt;strong&gt;something&lt;/strong&gt; they&amp;rsquo;re pushing towards and improving upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like its slowly killing me from the inside. Everyone else seems so&amp;hellip; relaxed. Like there&amp;rsquo;s just no care in the world. I put so much pressure on myself to the point where it&amp;rsquo;s detrimental. I feel like I can&amp;rsquo;t relate to anyone anymore. Perhaps I feel like this because I&amp;rsquo;ve been isolating for so long. I feel like there&amp;rsquo;s just&amp;hellip;. something deep down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clarifications&#34;&gt;Clarifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanna emphasize that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;above&amp;rdquo; others in any way. I&amp;rsquo;m not self-absorbed or yearning for social acceptance. I just, suddenly feel a massive disconnect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/MjXPTqy.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Taoism and Rastafarianism</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/420.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Taoism and Rastafarianism" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I want to emphasize that what I am about to say is highly subjective and is part of my personal interpretation.
I decided to write this because I find both fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;their-origins&#34;&gt;Their Origins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For context sake, Taoism has been around for a really long time; since around the 4th century, and started in China. Rastafarianism actually started as a political movement in the 1930s in Jamaica and emerged from the &lt;strong&gt;Abrahamic&lt;/strong&gt; religions, namely Christianity and Judaism and as such, is monotheistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also where the stark contrast between the two lies. The key word is movement. Rastafarianism never emerged solely because of religious values, but it is still essential and grounded in the movement. Taoism was purely philosophical, devoid of any politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-definition-of-religion&#34;&gt;The definition of Religion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Religion is a difficult word to define. I personally believe both these belief systems can be defined rather as a &amp;ldquo;Way of Life&amp;rdquo; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that when a &amp;lsquo;religion&amp;rsquo; has more strict beliefs, is unified and becomes widely institutionalized, it falls under the &amp;lsquo;religion&amp;rsquo; category. Example&amp;rsquo;s would be Christianity, Hinduism, Islam including their many respective forms and so on. However, that&amp;rsquo;s not to say places of worship for Taoism and Rastafarianism do not exist, because they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Taoism and Rastafari Culture embrace the idea of treading on your &lt;strong&gt;own&lt;/strong&gt; path to enlightenment, finding peace and content in life&amp;rsquo;s simple joys . Albeit in Rastafarianism it is much more of a collective effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/lol.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1200&#34;
	height=&#34;756&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/lol_hu6db0bf348c7f7ee1fb81ffaed16baf19_381117_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/lol_hu6db0bf348c7f7ee1fb81ffaed16baf19_381117_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;158&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;380px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nature-and-lifestyle&#34;&gt;Nature and Lifestyle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both beliefs, there is a lot of importance placed upon living in harmony and peace with nature.
It is by far the most &lt;strong&gt;crucial&lt;/strong&gt; aspect of both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that often in our day to day lives, we search for meaning and substance in material things.
We consume content, turn to the arts like literature and music, buy things we need or might not that serve some kind of purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end its all kinda just pointless depending on how you view it, at least it is for me.
When you stop for a second, take everything in and find peace and content by simply feeling and existing, that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/chillcat.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;500&#34;
	height=&#34;287&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/chillcat_hu496ab323a84514f468bbad3572766ea9_35475_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/chillcat_hu496ab323a84514f468bbad3572766ea9_35475_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;174&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;418px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How often, do you kinda just forget you have ownership of something? Or how often that one song or show you enjoyed eventually just slips out of your mind? The lessons and experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my life will never leave me. It feels much closer to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;diet&#34;&gt;Diet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rastas are primarily vegan. Their diet is called &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ital&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. They do this because it is believed that a diet free of additives, chemicals and meat is neccessary in order to stay healthy and more spiritually connected to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tao believe the same essentially; eating as close to natural as possible including little meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both discourage the consumption of substances such as nicotine and alcohol as well as other drugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both look down on political systems, violence and authoritarianism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to be vegetarian for around 4 months. Not because of the influences of any religion, mainly animal cruelty and because I honestly feel like humanity is a plague to the earth. Consuming meat is not a necessity by any pragmatical means.  Unfortunately I lost a significant amount of weight and it was quite difficult to have a diet different from my family&amp;rsquo;s without personal income. I plan on continuing once I am self-independent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-off&#34;&gt;Ending off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily &lt;em&gt;follow&lt;/em&gt; Taoism or Rastafarianism. There are aspects are disagree upon in both, more so in Rastafari Culture because of its misogynistic views.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>An Explanation on Ocean&#39;s 47</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/steez.jpg" alt="Featured image of post An Explanation on Ocean&#39;s 47" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The man above is Courtney Jamal Dewar Jr, more commonly known as &lt;strong&gt;Capital Steez&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-capital-steez&#34;&gt;Who is Capital Steez?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital Steez &lt;strong&gt;was&lt;/strong&gt;. He was a rapper from Brooklyn, New York.
He was part of the colletive group; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pro_Era&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pro Era&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro Era or rather the Progressive Era, started out as just a group of friends in highschool, including my favourite rapper, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joey_Badass&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Joey Bada$$&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;capital-steez---apex&#34;&gt;Capital Steez - Apex&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/huISHVRUPUA&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanation&#34;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into detail about Steez&amp;rsquo;s life.
He was Joey&amp;rsquo;s best friend and unfortunately committed suicide on the 23rd of December 2012.
The numbers on date on his death &lt;code&gt;12/23/12&lt;/code&gt; add up to 47.
His last message was &amp;ldquo;THE END&amp;rdquo;.
The next album in his career was going to be called &amp;ldquo;47 Shift&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;long-live-steelo-edit&#34;&gt;Long live Steelo Edit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U-RA22CIvpk&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just simply going to explain &amp;ldquo;Ocean&amp;rsquo;s 47&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to break it up into three parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number &lt;strong&gt;47&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The word &lt;strong&gt;Ocean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Links to &lt;strong&gt;Taoism / Daoism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oceans 47&amp;rdquo; is a line from the track &amp;ldquo;Ring the Alarm&amp;rdquo; by Joey Bada$$, Meechy Darko, Kirk Knight and Nyck Caution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;#34;Death before dishonor, I die for brethren
This is a stick-up, ocean&amp;#39;s 47
Ring the alarm...&amp;#34;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-number-47&#34;&gt;The Number 47&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steez was a leader. He told his peers to do something meaningful with their lives and they followed.
The number 47 would mean nothing to Pro Era without Steez.
Steez saw the number 47 as the perfect number. It is a prime number. The number 4, represents the 4th or &lt;strong&gt;Heart&lt;/strong&gt; Chakra. The number 7, represents the 7th or &lt;strong&gt;Crown&lt;/strong&gt; Chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Steez, its the balance of the heart and mind. The balance of logical and irrational thinking. He believed that when connecting with others, you need to be sympathetic and caring while also not being completely heartless and logical. Now there&amp;rsquo;s also the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.masonic-lodge-of-education.com/47th-problem-of-euclid.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;47th problem of Euclid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, more commonly known as the &lt;strong&gt;Pythagorean&lt;/strong&gt; theorem. There&amp;rsquo;s also connections with the number 47 and the &lt;strong&gt;Swastika&lt;/strong&gt; symbol. There is &lt;strong&gt;also&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;angel numbers&amp;rdquo; and many more stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unrelated to the &lt;strong&gt;number itself&lt;/strong&gt;, is the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://faculty.fiu.edu/~harrisk/Notes/Aesthetics/Apollonian-%20Dionysian%20Dichotomy.htm&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Apollonian&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dionysian&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - directly opposing (however not antithetical) sides of Greek Culture which Friedrich Nietzsche mentioned in his work, &amp;lsquo;The Birth of Tragedy&amp;rsquo;. These dualistic and opposing &amp;lsquo;forces&amp;rsquo; are represented by the two Greek Gods; Apollo and Dionysus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apollo represents reason, rationality, calm and fortitude.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dionysus represents impulse, emotion, instinct and chaos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In simplification, Nietzsche asserted that to be content with oneself is to control the balance of these two forces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ArsS6sPhwn0&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe there is anything significant about the number and it&amp;rsquo;s various connections really. It&amp;rsquo;s about what it represents to me.
Steez&amp;rsquo;s music was highly influential and had left a mark on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do believe that there needs to be a balance between the heart and mind. The number 47 represents this to me.
I think too rationally at times; to the point where I can&amp;rsquo;t connect with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-word-ocean&#34;&gt;The Word Ocean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;lyrics&lt;/strong&gt; of the song, &amp;ldquo;Ocean&amp;rdquo; was simply a reference to the movie &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0240772/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Oceans Eleven&amp;rdquo; (2001)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, it has a different meaning. When I think of an ocean, I think of water endlessly flowing and never resting. Waves crashing. From afar, it is still. On the shore, it exerts its tremendous kinetic energy on the surrounding area. In another blog I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about my trip to Japan, but it also reminds me of the Great Wave of Hokusai for this reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great-wave-of-hokusai&#34;&gt;The Great Wave of Hokusai&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/hokusai.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;800&#34;
	height=&#34;538&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/hokusai_hu12a289ef2460acfe1fa9dc9569991029_168910_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/hokusai_hu12a289ef2460acfe1fa9dc9569991029_168910_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Great Wave Off Kanagawa | Japanese: 神奈川沖浪裏&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;148&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;356px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wave dominates the composition, emphasizing its relative size in comparison to Mount Fuji behind it and the men that are rowing for their lives.
Its destructive when energetic, yet friendly and welcoming when its not.
In a similar fashion, I feel that when people are calm and collected, they are more approachable.
More present.
Their calming and understanding essence feels soothing and even &lt;em&gt;medicinal&lt;/em&gt;.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to be this kind of person to the people I care most about, while also not being completely rational and lacking empathy in some respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, I feel the word Ocean is strongly linked to the number 47. I don&amp;rsquo;t think lyrics necessarily have to have a single-defined meaning. Its fine to interpret them in your own way as you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;taosim&#34;&gt;Taosim&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/tao.png&#34;
	width=&#34;300&#34;
	height=&#34;300&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/tao_hu2ae312aa34be84bde18807b30339ef60_66252_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/tao_hu2ae312aa34be84bde18807b30339ef60_66252_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember back in highschool, we were tasked with researching a religion of our choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t even think Taoism is a &lt;em&gt;religion&lt;/em&gt; per say. Its more like a philosophy or a way of life.
Basically it focuses on a balanced way of living life. Living life in harmony and with nature.
Importantly, in Taoism, opposites rely on each other to coexist.
This is the &lt;em&gt;only religion&lt;/em&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever come across in my life that is the most sensible and agreeable for me personally.
In this way, its linked to the dualistic behaviour of the &lt;strong&gt;ocean&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;balance of chakras&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favourite quotes from Lao Tzu, the founding philosopher of Taoism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;When people see things as beautiful, ugliness is created. ~ Lao Tzu
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-off&#34;&gt;Ending Off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoyed this short read. TLDR: I believe that having a balance in life is important.
I highly recommend to check out some of Capital Steez&amp;rsquo;s music if enjoy you &amp;lsquo;Boom-Bap&amp;rsquo; as a subgenre or just rap in general.
Peace &amp;lt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/cutecat.png&#34;
	width=&#34;480&#34;
	height=&#34;360&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/cutecat_hu7fa53c326e10933a05760b6587936164_215111_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/cutecat_hu7fa53c326e10933a05760b6587936164_215111_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
