<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Fluff on Macawls&#39; Blog</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/categories/fluff/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Fluff on Macawls&#39; Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://macawls.github.io/blog/categories/fluff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>What is Limerence? 🧠</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/what-is-limerence/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/what-is-limerence/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/what-is-limerence/thumb.PNG" alt="Featured image of post What is Limerence? 🧠" /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/WUu39PJ_TI0&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to undertake therapy recently. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a significant change in my behavior and thoughts as a result of several events occurring in close interim, not necessarily because of a negative mental state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/v1.Y2lkPTc5MGI3NjExYmMxYzA4M2ZkZTg1NWY2YjhhNDE3NmVlZWExZmY1M2M1ZWYzZTBhYiZlcD12MV9pbnRlcm5hbF9naWZzX2dpZklkJmN0PWc/pMtLKNjb2IVXO/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last time I&amp;rsquo;d been in therapy was back in highschool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That experience taught me to immediately open-up as a sort of preventative measure of inadvertently remaining in a state of mental rumination, which in everyday conversation means &lt;em&gt;being in your own head&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all it&amp;rsquo;s worth I think thats fairly significant. Key things I&amp;rsquo;ve identified about myself include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being emotionally unavailable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Difficulty comprehending empathy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Putting a shield over my heart in order to protect myself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men are often taught to dismiss, disregard or suppress their emotions as a result of societal expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look up to my dad because he&amp;rsquo;s my superman. He never lets emotions cloud his judgement and I feel that I&amp;rsquo;m on the same path, although he is much more emotionally intelligent than I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I truly believe I have a strong sense of identity, but right now it feels like there&amp;rsquo;s many parts of myself that I selectively show to specific people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;mirror.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;260&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Why?&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do this in an attempt to min/max and allow everything I desire to manifest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;swift.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Am I delusional? Yes very much so 😎👍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I were to reflect on my past relationships, it seems that whenever I have shown vulnerability, it&amp;rsquo;s often backfired or resulted in negative consequences. As if the more exposed I am, the more I could invite unnecessary harm upon myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/M9mRuGEauiwCtfShtc/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;350&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how do we cultivate long lasting quality friendships without vulnerability? How do we nurture them without expressing emotions? That&amp;rsquo;s obviously not possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/ZtB2l3jHiJsFa/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across this term on the path to understanding myself more, called &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Limerence&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Limerence&lt;/a&gt; . I went on sort of a spiral with this term and it really intrigued me. From this point onwards the post will be less personal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-limerence&#34;&gt;What is Limerence?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;limerence&amp;rdquo; was coined by psychologist Dorothy Tennov in her book &amp;ldquo;Love and Limerence: The Experience of Being in Love,&amp;rdquo; which was first published in 1979. That was about four decades ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the term itself may not be widely known outside of psychology, the experiences and behaviors associated with limerence have been observed and discussed for a really long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limerence has been acknowledged as a psychological phenomenon and has garnered attention in the study of romantic relationships and attachment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a mental state characterized by infatuation, often in a romantic/sexual context. It involves being deeply captivated by someone, fixating on them, and experiencing strong yearning and longing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, limerence revolves around an idealized version of the person, crafted within one&amp;rsquo;s mind, rather than a true representation of who they are. This captivating state is involuntary, and individuals affected by limerence cannot easily control or choose their feelings towards the person of their infatuation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;rainbow.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life&amp;rsquo;s unpredictable nature never fails to astonish me. None of us truly know anything for sure, it&amp;rsquo;s as if we&amp;rsquo;re all blindly following one another. You would think that we have a choice on what intrigues us or the freedom to choose what we find captivating. Like the preconceived notion of what we supposedly find attractive is absolute when in reality that&amp;rsquo;s far from the truth. It&amp;rsquo;s all an illusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will return to limerence, for now I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to explore the definition of addiction since the two phenomena share some similarities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-addiction&#34;&gt;Understanding Addiction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
Our mind easily tricks us into thinking we&#39;re in control.
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/1L5YuA6wpKkNO/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, it may seem like we have a say in whether or not we engage in addictive behaviors. We might convince ourselves that we can stop at any time or that we have the willpower to resist temptation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
We might go on to say, &lt;i&gt;&#34;Oh yeah I can stop this thing for three weeks&#34;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a deeper level, the three weeks was always accomplishable, reinforcing the illusion that we&amp;rsquo;re in control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Delulu 🤪🤟
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not an arbitrary duration, it came from somewhere. The truth is that these self-imposed limits are meant to maintain the illusion of control rather than challenging the addictive patterns. Addiction operates on a deeper level, beyond the realm of conscious willpower. The cravings and ingrained patterns of behavior will persist, waiting for an opportunity to resurface and overpower our self-control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;doggo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
    &lt;i&gt;The sense of enlightenment is evident in [Figure 5], as this astute canine intently reads my post and makes a connection between its behavior and its owner&#39;s treats&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behaviors that trigger addictive responses activate the brain&amp;rsquo;s reward pathway, flooding it with dopamine. This flood of pleasure reinforces the desire to repeat the behavior, leading to a cycle of craving, indulgence, and temporary relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To truly grasp addiction, we need to recognize its complexities and understand that it&amp;rsquo;s not just about willpower or making choices. It&amp;rsquo;s a complicated condition that messes with our reward systems, our thoughts and behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/xT1R9LUBYOXB4b8E6Y/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To digress a little bit, &amp;lsquo;Chocolate boy&amp;rsquo; was a character in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hey_Arnold!&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hey Arnold&lt;/a&gt; that was a metaphor for substance abuse/addiction that aired on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nickelodeon&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Nickelodeon&lt;/a&gt;. Thought this was interesting to share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gYWYINshEag&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty dark for a children&amp;rsquo;s show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-link-between-addiction-and-limerence&#34;&gt;The Link Between Addiction and Limerence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While limerence is not synonymous with addiction, there are notable connections between the two that I&amp;rsquo;ll explore in the subtopics below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/lXu72d4iKwqek/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I dive into this section, I think its important to understand that limerence is not a bad thing. It&amp;rsquo;s a natural phenomenon completely out of our control. However, it can be harmful if we can&amp;rsquo;t recognize or comprehend the extent of its effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;similar-neurochemical-processes&#34;&gt;Similar Neurochemical Processes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both experiences involve the release of dopamine. In addiction, substances or behaviors trigger dopamine release, reinforcing the desire to repeat the behavior. Similarly, during limerence, the presence or even the mere thought of the desired person can stimulate dopamine release, stimulating pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/38tjCITcNUmWc/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;330&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;obsessive-nature-and-compulsive-behavior&#34;&gt;Obsessive Nature and Compulsive Behavior&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limerence often manifests as an obsessive preoccupation. Individuals experiencing limerence may engage in repetitive thoughts, daydreaming, and fantasizing about the desired person. This nature bears resemblance to the compulsive behaviors observed in addiction. Both limerence and addiction can drive individuals to engage in repetitive and sometimes harmful actions, even against logical judgement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/3o7aDdyo3zIa5aJKG4/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;320&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;escapism-and-emotional-dependence&#34;&gt;Escapism and Emotional Dependence&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both addiction and limerence can serve as forms of escapism or emotional coping mechanisms. People may turn to addictive substances or behaviors, as well as limerent fantasies, to escape from reality, numb emotional pain, or find solace. In both cases, the underlying motivation often stems from a desire to fulfill unmet emotional needs or seek temporary relief from psychological distress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/xT0Gqu0s3j4auj4QP6/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;280&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;interference-with-daily-functioning&#34;&gt;Interference with Daily Functioning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Addiction and limerence can significantly impact daily functioning and overall well-being. Both can consume a person&amp;rsquo;s thoughts, making it challenging to focus on other aspects of life. The pursuit of the addictive substance or the limerent person can overshadow responsibilities, relationships, and personal goals, leading to disruptions in various areas of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/vWye6xPB61oZ7Mx8hq/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;320&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-difference-between-love-and-limerence&#34;&gt;The Difference between Love and Limerence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s a necessity for me to explain what love is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distinction between love and limerence is often a source of confusion. They&amp;rsquo;re sort of a union. Both involve intense feelings for another person but there are important differences to consider. Whats even more confusing is,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limerence can evolve into love over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love can evolve into limerence over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love and limerence can coexist or evolve over time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making it even more difficult to distinguish between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media.giphy.com/media/RsovLXVXN8BKo/giphy.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;450&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, in the early stages of a romantic relationship, limerence may be more prevalent, while love develops and deepens over time as the relationship matures. In rare cases, limerence may even develop in the context of an existing long-term relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-differences&#34;&gt;Key Differences&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limerence is often accompanied by feelings of anxiety and uncertainty, whereas love is secure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is a deep affection and attachment to someone that has stood the test of time, whereas limerence is typically a short-lived infatuation with someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limerence is a state of mind that can be triggered by a romantic interest, whereas love is a stable commitment to someone regardless of whether or not the person is reciprocating feelings of affection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limerence is often characterized by obsessive thoughts and fantasies about the desired person, whereas love is more grounded in reality and involves a deeper, more unconditional acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;evolutionary-perspective-on-limerence&#34;&gt;Evolutionary Perspective on Limerence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reproduction is a fundamental part of human nature. It&amp;rsquo;s a biological imperative that has been ingrained in our DNA through millions of years of evolution. The drive for limerence is a byproduct of this evolutionary process and it&amp;rsquo;s almost always associated with lust, romantic or sexual desire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;bra.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
Why? 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put simply, its a mechanism that helps us find a suitable mate and increase the likelihood of survival for our offspring. The heightened state of arousal and infatuation limerence induces leads people to engage in behaviors that are conducive to attracting and maintaining a romantic partner, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efforts in courtship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Displays of affection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emotional bonding&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;modern-day-implications-of-limerence-in-relationships&#34;&gt;Modern Day Implications of Limerence in Relationships&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While limerence may have evolved as an adaptive mechanism for mate selection specifically, it is not the sole determinant of successful long-term relationships. Factors such as compatibility, shared values, communication styles, emotional connection and commitment also play significant roles in the formation and maintenance of relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limerence can sometimes be so powerful that it can overshadow these factors and possibly lead to an imbalanced and unsustainable relationship dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-off&#34;&gt;Ending Off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed writing this post, was a fun topic to explore.
I think its important to understand the science behind limerence and how it affects our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had no idea that a term for this phenomena even existed. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are many people out there who are experiencing this and don&amp;rsquo;t know what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed reading it as much as I enjoyed writing it. It seems like most of my non-technical posts are leaning into the psychology side of things and I&amp;rsquo;m all for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;duck.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have an amazing day ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The future of this blog</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/the-future-of-this-blog/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/the-future-of-this-blog/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/the-future-of-this-blog/pc.jpg" alt="Featured image of post The future of this blog" /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CPkkgLoZTzY&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is gonna sound poetic as fuck but my blog was supposed to be space where I could unearth the depths of my being. Typing on the keyboard was supposed to capture the sensation of reaching into the darkest parts of my psyche that never made it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, writing provides a similar healing energy to dancing, with the added benefit of being able to revisit my past thoughts. In short, this supposed to be was my sanctuary, my haven, my refuge, exactly how I described it back in December of 2021 on my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/about/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;About Page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire point of the blog was to be a free space for myself where I could write about whatever I want, whenever I want, without any restrictions. I&amp;rsquo;ve realized the more people I share this blog with, the trickier it becomes to write about things. In the early days, back when it just was me, myself and I, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have this blog deployed and a domain setup yet, I felt completely free and my creative juices were absolutely fuming. I entered the flow state when writing with barely any effort. I would &lt;em&gt;reeeealllly&lt;/em&gt;  like that back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s frustrating about the brainstorming process for blog post ideas is, I can&amp;rsquo;t exactly be completely transparent.
I brainstorm as much as I did at the start of the blog back in 2021, but don&amp;rsquo;t write posts as frequently as I did back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blog is entirely publicly accessible. If I give the blog to my colleagues it introduces a restriction whereby I can&amp;rsquo;t write about things that are &amp;ldquo;inappropriate&amp;rdquo; for a work environment. If I give it to my friends or family I cannot mention people or experiences that are too personal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I need to be careful about what I write about. That wasn&amp;rsquo;t the initial purpose of my blog. It has most definitely lost its purpose over time. All of the content on the blog will remain the same and I won&amp;rsquo;t be deleting any posts. However, the blog will now be a place where I&amp;rsquo;ll only share things that I&amp;rsquo;m completely comfortable with sharing publicly, so it&amp;rsquo;ll become a lot less personal. I&amp;rsquo;ll still be writing about things that I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about and interested in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My Recent Shenanigans [Actually Good Content]</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/my-recent-shenanigans-actually-good-content/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/my-recent-shenanigans-actually-good-content/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/my-recent-shenanigans-actually-good-content/thumb.png" alt="Featured image of post My Recent Shenanigans [Actually Good Content]" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a heavy fluff post.
I&amp;rsquo;m just gonna talk about some of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to recently.
Most peeps are out of the country or in different cities so I&amp;rsquo;ve been chilling at home, working on stuff and listening to music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;random&#34;&gt;Random&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend and I were trying to see if we could find each other&amp;rsquo;s names on google. I randomly found this guy who did a playthrough of my game!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aviWojbsjKw&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe how happy I was just seeing him smile. Dat warm fuzzy feeling. 😌&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Meme: Zoomer vs Boomer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;video width=&#34;600&#34; controls&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;meme.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt; 
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah yes, the usual list of recent bangers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hardtekk == 😌💗&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I unironically used a double &amp;lsquo;=&amp;rsquo; sign. Wow. I&amp;rsquo;m not even gonna edit it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1355652571&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s originally a german rap song. I have no idea what they&amp;rsquo;re saying, but it&amp;rsquo;s so catchy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/732325759&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last drop is 🤙&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1415851762&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emo angle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1400137843&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;favourite&#34;&gt;Favourite&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Sometimes I can’t feel movement
But we moving
What’s the scale of, your improvement?
What’s the tale of, your success tho? 
Is it hard work, was it dress code?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iweo6_2d_ew&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;festival-experience&#34;&gt;Festival Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to the Little Forest Festival about maybe a month ago. It was a pretty cool experience. We had a group of about 6 people and I only knew 1 of them. So that made me feel a bit reserved.
If I was comfortable in the group and the environment I think I would&amp;rsquo;ve had a better time and definitely better trips if u know what I&amp;rsquo;m saying. It was still awesome though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bruh sometimes I just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know the time or the day. It was just a blur of music and people. The music never stopped for 3 days. I was just vibing the whole time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XfquchmuNjc&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;re-doing-my-personal-website&#34;&gt;Re-doing my Personal Website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah. I am shit at webdev at the moment.  I haven&amp;rsquo;t really done any proper web development work and it&amp;rsquo;s all very new to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t really do any web dev stuff in my University. Not serious dev work. Theres only like figma users in the digital design department or something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me whats confusing is that there&amp;rsquo;s so many tools and frameworks and just like &lt;strong&gt;stuff&lt;/strong&gt; to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a SPA? Client-Side? SSR? SSG? Routing? Hydration? Webpack? Dafuq is going on??? 😄&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a while back I decided I was gonna learn how to use Vue. So I did sorta and then I rage quit because of responsive design and css. And thats not even vue specific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I decided to come back to it in the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like, working with anything web dev related always feels like playdough snakes to me. It feels finniky and I don&amp;rsquo;t like it. It always feels like there&amp;rsquo;s so much abstraction and I&amp;rsquo;m just not sure what&amp;rsquo;s going on. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if I&amp;rsquo;m just being dumb or if I&amp;rsquo;m just not used to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But alas, the website is up and running for everyone&amp;rsquo;s viewing pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://macawls.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/Macawls/macawls.github.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Github Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Dang, now what?</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/dang-now-what/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/dang-now-what/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/dang-now-what/tv.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Dang, now what?" /&gt;&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;ENDED THE SEMESTER A COUPLE WEEKS AGO 🥳🎉 LESGOOOOO&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
 &lt;video width=&#34;400&#34;  controls&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;friday-night.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was really happy with the results. Pure relief man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dreads are getting hella long now which is dope. I didn&amp;rsquo;t re-twist AND cut them since the start exams and it&amp;rsquo;s been bothering me so much. I just was just a caveman wearing a beanie everyday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went clubbing before exams and I lost my wallet that night. I drove to campus every single day without a license, no credit card and no ID. Professional dumbass 😎👍.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I finally have time now to sort these things out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being home is kinda boring tho not gonna lie. But I got a couple things to keep me busy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;tv.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;250&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-im-working-on---prototype&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m working on - Prototype&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;video
    controls
    src=&#34;prototype-vid.mp4&#34;
    
    
    &gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Your browser doesn&#39;t support HTML5 video. Here is a
            &lt;a href=&#34;prototype-vid.mp4&#34;&gt;link to the video&lt;/a&gt; instead.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a state machine package for unity recently. Its still in development but I wanted to test it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really love &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celeste_%28video_game%29&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Celeste&lt;/a&gt; , it&amp;rsquo;s one of my favourite games and I really wanna recreate some aspects of it. Something mixed with celestes parkour and some survival/dungeon elements would be cool. The problem is celeste&amp;rsquo;s character controller is like 2k lines alone, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been rewriting it in a modular fashion where I hopefully just pop it into another game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;recent-events-and-stuff&#34;&gt;Recent Events and Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got my first &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.toxyngames.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;internship&lt;/a&gt; which is dope.
Whats great about it is that it&amp;rsquo;s during the holidays so it won&amp;rsquo;t affect me next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I wen&amp;rsquo;t to this &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://gamesweek.africa/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;game dev/design event&lt;/a&gt; called Africa Games Week recently.
It was pretty cool. Enjoyed the people more than anything else to be honest. There were talks but I personally didn&amp;rsquo;t find them all that interesting because they weren&amp;rsquo;t technical type talks. More like overview type talks.
Generally, really enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still can&amp;rsquo;t believe it though dawg, I met &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/thea_booysen/?hl=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Thea Booysen&lt;/a&gt; on the first day, of whom is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MrBeast&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mr Beast&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; current girlfriend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like bro, wtf what are the odds. Why it was so suprising is because she was incredibly down to earth and so friendly. I was genuinely shocked after I found out later. So far all the &amp;ldquo;celebs&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve met include Jack Parow, Marc Lottering and Riaad Moosa of whom are all local SA celebs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But like, whats different compared to the previous instances was I had no idea of her being &amp;lsquo;famous&amp;rsquo;. I just conversed normally like it was any other person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Epic shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-now&#34;&gt;What now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idk. I&amp;rsquo;ll work on da prototype and relax in the holidays.
Cya bros 😸🤜🤛😁.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;video
    controls
    src=&#34;cat.mp4&#34;
    
    
    &gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Your browser doesn&#39;t support HTML5 video. Here is a
            &lt;a href=&#34;cat.mp4&#34;&gt;link to the video&lt;/a&gt; instead.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Can relationships be non-transactional?</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/can-relationships-be-non-transactional/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/can-relationships-be-non-transactional/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/can-relationships-be-non-transactional/banner.png" alt="Featured image of post Can relationships be non-transactional?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The pictures have no relation to the post whatsoever. I just find them funny 😎👍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about this a couple days ago. About why in some instances I seem to have zero interest in improving relationships with people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think when we&amp;rsquo;re younger we seem to have no problem with this. We&amp;rsquo;re more open to new things in general because our lack of life experience. We&amp;rsquo;re more willing to put in the effort to make things work and most importantly, &lt;strong&gt;more malleable and impressionable&lt;/strong&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;re still developing our own identity and are more willing to change our own beliefs and values to fit in with others. That&amp;rsquo;s completely normal because its in our human nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;pog.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the threshold for a relatively acceptable level of trust is much lower. We&amp;rsquo;re more willing to trust others and are more willing to give them the benefit of the doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-personal-experience&#34;&gt;My personal experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;yo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;200&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a moderately introverted person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During school and highschool I sorta let my friends &lt;strong&gt;choose me&lt;/strong&gt; and I kinda just went with it. Only thing I cared about was fitting in. In general I was very open to new people and even if someone was ostracized, I&amp;rsquo;d still be willing to talk to them. This is still true as of now but to a lesser extent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-things-have-changed&#34;&gt;How things have changed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been through so much in this past year and it has definitely been one of the most challenging and rewarding years of my life. I&amp;rsquo;d say the main theme of this year was loss. I can&amp;rsquo;t really go into too much detail since this blog is public, but I&amp;rsquo;ve lost quite a few people in my life this year, some of which I had trusted and considered friends. I&amp;rsquo;ve also lost family members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, certain people are not worth your time. And thats okay!
You&amp;rsquo;ve gotta listen to that inner voice that tells you that something is wrong.
You&amp;rsquo;ve gotta trust your gut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you&amp;rsquo;ve gotta be selfish. You&amp;rsquo;ve gotta put yourself first. You&amp;rsquo;ve gotta put your own needs first over everything else, &lt;strong&gt;no matter what&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-every-relationship-is-transactional&#34;&gt;Why every relationship is transactional&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot ever see myself being in a relationship with someone where I&amp;rsquo;m not getting anything out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying&lt;/strong&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;m only in relationships with people who can give me something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m saying&lt;/strong&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;m only in relationships with people who can give me something &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; I can give them something in return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-this-important&#34;&gt;Why is this important?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is a transactional imbalance, the relationship is un-sustainable. No matter how much you try to make it work, it will eventually fail. What is an imbalance? Put simply it means that one person is giving more than the other. During a relationship its normal for the balance to shift occasionally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is really important. The transaction &lt;strong&gt;CANNOT&lt;/strong&gt; be driven by ulterior motives. For example, you might decide to pursue a relationship where you give more than you receive in order to get something out of it. You start to assume that the other person will eventually give you something in return. I myself am guilty of this and it&amp;rsquo;s a very dangerous mindset to have. People &lt;strong&gt;DO NOT&lt;/strong&gt; work like investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It &lt;strong&gt;HAS&lt;/strong&gt; to be driven by genuine interest in the other person. You have to genuinely care about the other person and want to see them succeed. You have to genuinely want to help them and be there for them. You have to genuinely want to see them happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t feel like this, is it really worth it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;schizo.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically no. Relationships cannot be non-transactional. One might argue that family relationships are non-transactional. I&amp;rsquo;d argue that they are. The reason why is because together, you&amp;rsquo;ve established a level of trust and care that is beneficial to both parties. Personally I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in blood being thicker than water. I think that family relationships are just as transactional as any other relationship. People are people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;thumbsup.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;random&#34;&gt;Random&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outta context. Really enjoyed this movie recently. Absolutely beautiful. Highly recommend it, its dope 😎👍&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p6yN-78_ROY&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>😹🍓 emF6aWUgYmVldHogaXMgbXkgY2VsZWJyaXR5IGNydXNo</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/emf6awugymvldhogaxmgbxkgy2vszwjyaxr5ignydxno/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/emf6awugymvldhogaxmgbxkgy2vszwjyaxr5ignydxno/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/GQiTPCd.jpg" alt="Featured image of post 😹🍓 emF6aWUgYmVldHogaXMgbXkgY2VsZWJyaXR5IGNydXNo" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm I think this will be a filler type of post.
You can decode the title and description from Base64.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know whats crazy is, I realized that I love programming so fucking much.
At a high level it&amp;rsquo;s just editing text, solving problems and making stuff. Being at my pc for hours doesn&amp;rsquo;t bother me in the slightest. It&amp;rsquo;s so fucking comfy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/emf6awugymvldhogaxmgbxkgy2vszwjyaxr5ignydxno/balling.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;320&#34;
	height=&#34;320&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/emf6awugymvldhogaxmgbxkgy2vszwjyaxr5ignydxno/balling_hu3d665cbc421f3459a5d9e050773c4565_21699_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/emf6awugymvldhogaxmgbxkgy2vszwjyaxr5ignydxno/balling_hu3d665cbc421f3459a5d9e050773c4565_21699_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;blog-ideas&#34;&gt;Blog ideas&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some blog ideas lined up incluing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The History of Bell Labs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognition - STEM Displicines(e.g scientific) vs Visual/Auditorial Disciplines(e.g playing guitar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idk how to explain the last one, basically its easy for normies to gauge your level of expertise and progress if you&amp;rsquo;re a dancer/gym person/photographer/musician.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For abstract STEM fields its alot more difficult unless you have basic knowledge of the field itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/emf6awugymvldhogaxmgbxkgy2vszwjyaxr5ignydxno/yaya.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;216&#34;
	height=&#34;218&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/emf6awugymvldhogaxmgbxkgy2vszwjyaxr5ignydxno/yaya_hub244791676407d1b7b14d98784d730c9_34190_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/emf6awugymvldhogaxmgbxkgy2vszwjyaxr5ignydxno/yaya_hub244791676407d1b7b14d98784d730c9_34190_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;99&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;237px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanna make a blog post about my dreams and aspirations eventually, the writing process will help me understand myself more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a good day you beautiful human 🥰&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;video
    controls
    src=&#34;drinkwater.mp4&#34;
    
    
    &gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Your browser doesn&#39;t support HTML5 video. Here is a
            &lt;a href=&#34;drinkwater.mp4&#34;&gt;link to the video&lt;/a&gt; instead.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>DALL·E is kinda fucking crazy</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/dalle-is-kinda-fucking-crazy/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/dalle-is-kinda-fucking-crazy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/dalle-is-kinda-fucking-crazy/openai.png" alt="Featured image of post DALL·E is kinda fucking crazy" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;can-i-try-it-out&#34;&gt;Can I try it out?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes kinda.&lt;br&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s far too powerful of a tool to be easily accessible to the masses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/dalle-is-kinda-fucking-crazy/smol.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;125&#34;
	height=&#34;101&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/dalle-is-kinda-fucking-crazy/smol_hu3cabb017450616c2ca21b5c7096f29d1_1442_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/dalle-is-kinda-fucking-crazy/smol_hu3cabb017450616c2ca21b5c7096f29d1_1442_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;123&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;297px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, it took &lt;strong&gt;3 months&lt;/strong&gt; of being in the &lt;strong&gt;waiting list&lt;/strong&gt; to get access. &lt;br&gt;
I was given 45 tries. For every other subsequent month I get 15 tries. Forking out &lt;strong&gt;$15&lt;/strong&gt; gets me another &lt;strong&gt;115 tries&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-can-it-do&#34;&gt;What can it do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So pretty much, you supply a text prompt describing the kind of image you want to generate.
The AI takes care of the rest. It understands the relationship between objects insanely well and can even generate images in a specific artsyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After supplying the prompt, it took just a moment for it to generate 4 unique images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results are just absolutely mind-boggling and it&amp;rsquo;ll only improve over-time.&lt;br&gt;
All of these images are unique and cannot be found online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-best-results&#34;&gt;My Best Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially it started out with sub-par results because I wasn&amp;rsquo;t specific enough.&lt;br&gt;
Over time I learnt how to optimize my prompts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cat-listening-to-music&#34;&gt;Cat listening to music&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;A cat studying at a desk listing to music through studio monitors in cartoonish kawaii style&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/2Eiiajo.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/YiFQpxT.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/WRyanWW.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sad-cat-with-hoodie&#34;&gt;Sad Cat with Hoodie&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;A sad looking white cat looking down wearing a black hoodie in a digital art style&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/rr2zlez.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/Jtuz6Pm.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/Obz0FKR.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;panda-flying&#34;&gt;Panda Flying&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;A flying panda wearing a pink beanie in vector art style&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/Xm1hJuk.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/y9B7CUC.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;capybara-driving&#34;&gt;Capybara Driving&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;A capybara driving a luxury sports car in at sunset vapourwave aesthetic&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/XLf9xGg.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/z9WCVt7.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;laptop-dancing-in-a-disco&#34;&gt;Laptop Dancing in a Disco&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;a biped laptop dancing in a disco in pop art style&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/uw5zPwP.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/T2c2Yz6.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/6iiJlHK.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dog-in-space&#34;&gt;Dog in Space&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;retro art deco of a dog flying in space&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/FTLiNhs.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/durShwt.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/IBtwfpa.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Bangers 🎵 | Part 3</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/bangers-part-3/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/bangers-part-3/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/bangers-part-3/bg.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Bangers 🎵 | Part 3" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I love the eerie feeling. Carries so much weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1291922752&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refreshing feel happy kinda hardstyle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1301895715&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve heard Joey again. Missed his old style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1999_%28mixtape%29&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;1999&lt;/a&gt; is still my favourite album of all time.
Can&amp;rsquo;t wait till his new album 2000 drops in a couple days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/XoZtqXNLcW8&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Alienation</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/alienation/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/alienation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/v1OKSxN.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Alienation" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro---context&#34;&gt;Intro - Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an insane amount of freedom and agency these days.
I go to campus/classes whenever I like.
My parents pretty much allow me to do &lt;strong&gt;anything I want&lt;/strong&gt; because they trust me, I&amp;rsquo;m responsible and I don&amp;rsquo;t do dumb shit.
With my car(absolutely blessed), I can literally go wherever I want or need. Whats weird is that, I&amp;rsquo;ve been going out less often than before.
Something has me feeling off recently&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-ive-been-feeling&#34;&gt;How I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year was my first year of university and it was great. I was settling in, met a bunch of new people and it was generally pretty exciting throughout. I had a great balance of work and social life. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have as much agency as I do now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling a &lt;strong&gt;huge&lt;/strong&gt; social disconnect.
At the same time, I&amp;rsquo;ve been excelling in my aspirations and school work, &lt;strong&gt;far more&lt;/strong&gt; than I did last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, thats great right? On the other hand, I don&amp;rsquo;t have the close relationships I had last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, when I do accomplish something I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of, its kinda important for me to recieve some kind of feedback or just idk, something yknow? I feel like the more I progress the more people seem to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activities&#34;&gt;Activities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go out fairly often and it&amp;rsquo;s not like I don&amp;rsquo;t have friends around. But when I do, whether its going out clubbing or chilling at a friends place, I go because I feel like its important to be &lt;strong&gt;included&lt;/strong&gt;.
I know that I won&amp;rsquo;t be studying forever so I have this fear deep down that I&amp;rsquo;ll miss out on social experiences.
I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy hanging out as much as I used to anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I literally do not care about anyone, which is such a shitty thing to say, but I genuinely feel like this.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;m constantly surrounded by so many people I could reach out and talk to, but I don&amp;rsquo;t. I just do not care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People around me are constantly talking about this new food place, or this new club, or this new game, or this new movie, or this person on instagram or whatever and it&amp;rsquo;s so difficult to participate because the conversation doesn&amp;rsquo;t really engage me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I do talk about the things I&amp;rsquo;m personally interested in, which is technology and psychology topics, I feel like a buzzkill. I have quite controversial opinions and hot takes on topics that &lt;strong&gt;many&lt;/strong&gt; people disagree with or struggle to comprehend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, when I do talk about things that interest me, I talk sooooo much and can never summarize it from a high level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I feel like I can never just be honest and be myself. Obviously I do not want to offend anyone, that&amp;rsquo;s the last thing I&amp;rsquo;d want to do. Maybe its a self-confidence/fear issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;life-goals&#34;&gt;Life Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I respect very few of my peers. The only people I &lt;strong&gt;respect&lt;/strong&gt;, are people that are driven and constantly working on extra things, which in my university(rich kids) is incredibly rare to be honest. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what it is, could be work, could be health, could be hobbies, as long as its &lt;strong&gt;something&lt;/strong&gt; they&amp;rsquo;re pushing towards and improving upon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel like its slowly killing me from the inside. Everyone else seems so&amp;hellip; relaxed. Like there&amp;rsquo;s just no care in the world. I put so much pressure on myself to the point where it&amp;rsquo;s detrimental. I feel like I can&amp;rsquo;t relate to anyone anymore. Perhaps I feel like this because I&amp;rsquo;ve been isolating for so long. I feel like there&amp;rsquo;s just&amp;hellip;. something deep down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;clarifications&#34;&gt;Clarifications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanna emphasize that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;above&amp;rdquo; others in any way. I&amp;rsquo;m not self-absorbed or yearning for social acceptance. I just, suddenly feel a massive disconnect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/MjXPTqy.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Mood</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/mood/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/mood/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/mood/dead.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Mood" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ignorance and emotion blinds us all. The end of the world is imminent, either to artificial intelligence or global warming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology was a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re driven by greed and pleasure. Humanity is a plague. We&amp;rsquo;re divided by borders, religion and other arbitrary things. We only believe in things that follow our narrative. The rich get richer. Everyone lives as a puppet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well anyways, who cares lol :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/mood/smol.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;125&#34;
	height=&#34;101&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/mood/smol_hu3cabb017450616c2ca21b5c7096f29d1_1442_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/mood/smol_hu3cabb017450616c2ca21b5c7096f29d1_1442_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;123&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;297px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Taoism and Rastafarianism</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/420.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Taoism and Rastafarianism" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I want to emphasize that what I am about to say is highly subjective and is part of my personal interpretation.
I decided to write this because I find both fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;their-origins&#34;&gt;Their Origins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For context sake, Taoism has been around for a really long time; since around the 4th century, and started in China. Rastafarianism actually started as a political movement in the 1930s in Jamaica and emerged from the &lt;strong&gt;Abrahamic&lt;/strong&gt; religions, namely Christianity and Judaism and as such, is monotheistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also where the stark contrast between the two lies. The key word is movement. Rastafarianism never emerged solely because of religious values, but it is still essential and grounded in the movement. Taoism was purely philosophical, devoid of any politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-definition-of-religion&#34;&gt;The definition of Religion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Religion is a difficult word to define. I personally believe both these belief systems can be defined rather as a &amp;ldquo;Way of Life&amp;rdquo; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that when a &amp;lsquo;religion&amp;rsquo; has more strict beliefs, is unified and becomes widely institutionalized, it falls under the &amp;lsquo;religion&amp;rsquo; category. Example&amp;rsquo;s would be Christianity, Hinduism, Islam including their many respective forms and so on. However, that&amp;rsquo;s not to say places of worship for Taoism and Rastafarianism do not exist, because they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Taoism and Rastafari Culture embrace the idea of treading on your &lt;strong&gt;own&lt;/strong&gt; path to enlightenment, finding peace and content in life&amp;rsquo;s simple joys . Albeit in Rastafarianism it is much more of a collective effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/lol.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1200&#34;
	height=&#34;756&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/lol_hu6db0bf348c7f7ee1fb81ffaed16baf19_381117_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/lol_hu6db0bf348c7f7ee1fb81ffaed16baf19_381117_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;158&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;380px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nature-and-lifestyle&#34;&gt;Nature and Lifestyle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both beliefs, there is a lot of importance placed upon living in harmony and peace with nature.
It is by far the most &lt;strong&gt;crucial&lt;/strong&gt; aspect of both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that often in our day to day lives, we search for meaning and substance in material things.
We consume content, turn to the arts like literature and music, buy things we need or might not that serve some kind of purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end its all kinda just pointless depending on how you view it, at least it is for me.
When you stop for a second, take everything in and find peace and content by simply feeling and existing, that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/chillcat.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;500&#34;
	height=&#34;287&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/chillcat_hu496ab323a84514f468bbad3572766ea9_35475_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/chillcat_hu496ab323a84514f468bbad3572766ea9_35475_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;174&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;418px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How often, do you kinda just forget you have ownership of something? Or how often that one song or show you enjoyed eventually just slips out of your mind? The lessons and experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my life will never leave me. It feels much closer to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;diet&#34;&gt;Diet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rastas are primarily vegan. Their diet is called &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ital&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. They do this because it is believed that a diet free of additives, chemicals and meat is neccessary in order to stay healthy and more spiritually connected to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tao believe the same essentially; eating as close to natural as possible including little meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both discourage the consumption of substances such as nicotine and alcohol as well as other drugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both look down on political systems, violence and authoritarianism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to be vegetarian for around 4 months. Not because of the influences of any religion, mainly animal cruelty and because I honestly feel like humanity is a plague to the earth. Consuming meat is not a necessity by any pragmatical means.  Unfortunately I lost a significant amount of weight and it was quite difficult to have a diet different from my family&amp;rsquo;s without personal income. I plan on continuing once I am self-independent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-off&#34;&gt;Ending off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily &lt;em&gt;follow&lt;/em&gt; Taoism or Rastafarianism. There are aspects are disagree upon in both, more so in Rastafari Culture because of its misogynistic views.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Bangers 🎵 | Part 2</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/bangers-part-2/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/bangers-part-2/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/bangers-part-2/monkee.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Bangers 🎵 | Part 2" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Random genres this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just an absolute banger this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1164496222&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beam just switches up flows like crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PmvPweUMPCE&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love the mellow vibes on this track. That synth too omg. Really catchy. A ton of big names behind production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/syNGDDMYQzg&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love singing along to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6XLLl1AyjD8&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My New Honda Crz (2011)</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/my-new-honda-crz-2011/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/my-new-honda-crz-2011/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/my-new-honda-crz-2011/cocoa.jpg" alt="Featured image of post My New Honda Crz (2011)" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The picture looks like a terrible photoshop but things are blurred for privacy reasons.
Her name is Cocoa. No meaning behind the name, I just love calling her Cocoa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a massive fan of Japanese culture, JDM culture included. I&amp;rsquo;ll make a blog post about my previous trip to Japan soon. I make a lotta of references to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/STwMPHZNkME&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-like-the-car&#34;&gt;Why I like the car&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sounds kinda silly but back in the day of playing a bunch of Need for Speeds on an old PS2, I would always grab a Japanese car like the Mazda RX-8, Miata, Nissan Silva, Honda Civics etc (you get the point) and just have fun messing with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like the idea of really making something &lt;strong&gt;yours&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s also why I like linux so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s what I love about older cars, you get more bang for your buck and have so much more freedom and modularity available to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying something completely new (relatively expensive and long-term) makes me feel unhappy? Like I&amp;rsquo;m getting ripped off. I never buy anything where the emphasis is on the &lt;em&gt;brand&lt;/em&gt; and not &lt;em&gt;value for money&lt;/em&gt;. Mini-Coopers/Beats Headphones are a good examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like unique and unpopular things too. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s because I like standing out and being different or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;test-driving-the-crz&#34;&gt;Test-driving the CRZ&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It ticked all the boxes for me. The second I got in, the interior blew me away. It&amp;rsquo;s not NA, Steering wheel is on the right side for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/my-new-honda-crz-2011/interior.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1600&#34;
	height=&#34;1200&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/my-new-honda-crz-2011/interior_hue515a5873b1eb36dc4b1e4016fe7a5cf_469057_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/my-new-honda-crz-2011/interior_hue515a5873b1eb36dc4b1e4016fe7a5cf_469057_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Interior&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 2011, it was very modern. It was comfy, a really smooth drive, pretty damn responsive in sport mode, manual transmission, great sound system, hatchback, great fuel economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only downside is that it&amp;rsquo;s a two-seater primarily but I mean, 4 people is &lt;strong&gt;possible&lt;/strong&gt;. Its just insanely uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buying-process&#34;&gt;Buying process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of getting a car was threefold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My brother need transport for university.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The car I had been driving for a year(my Mom&amp;rsquo;s) had too many problems and she did not want to sell it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsurprisingly, &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; needed my own personal transport for the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed a decent, clean, safe and relatively new hatchback.
After test driving a bunch, my other options came down to the Renault Kwid(2020), Mini-Cooper(2012) and Honda Civic 2.2 CDTi(2011).
For &lt;strong&gt;necessity&lt;/strong&gt; sake, they were fine, checked all the boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;renault-kwid&#34;&gt;Renault Kwid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kwid was just not fun to drive. Engine was tiny. The clutch felt really weird. I remember just lifting the boot and it felt incredibly light. On the highway, it has a tendency to sway a little bit and it just felt extremely cheap. The car was meant to be a student car, produced cheaply for the masses. It sells extremely well and is in abundance here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mini-cooper&#34;&gt;Mini Cooper&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cooper was great. It had all the bells and whistles, was fun to drive, space for everyone and the sound system was amazing.
It was pretty old though with 160K km on the clock. My only concern was repairing. Repairing a Cooper is not fun and most importantly, it&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;strong&gt;cheap&lt;/strong&gt;. After driving the CRZ, I knew my heart belonged to it but I &lt;strong&gt;might&amp;rsquo;ve&lt;/strong&gt; gone with the Cooper if the deal with the CRZ wasn&amp;rsquo;t possible. &lt;strong&gt;Maybe&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;honda-civic-22-cdti&#34;&gt;Honda Civic 2.2 CDTi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This thing was a fucking &lt;strong&gt;monster&lt;/strong&gt;. It was sooo damn responsive and stupid fast. It was so much fun to drive. Definitely the most fun car to drive out of the bunch. The problem was it was unnecessarily fast, dangerous and way too old(wasn&amp;rsquo;t looked after well). I needed a reliable daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-plans&#34;&gt;Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll need another car eventually once I settle down, something more family oriented. Instead of replacing the CRZ I&amp;rsquo;m gonna do a K swap and Cocoa will become a project car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;K swap&amp;rdquo; means taking a Honda K series engine and putting it into something that didn&amp;rsquo;t come with a Honda K series engine. Pretty self-explanatory. The problem is, I&amp;rsquo;ll lose all the economy features but I mean you can&amp;rsquo;t really save the environment if you wanna go fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either the k20 or k24. Its in abundance here, really easy to find and relatively cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-hDt0pnHgtg&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My Monster Collection</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/my-monster-collection/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/my-monster-collection/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/my-monster-collection/cans.jpg" alt="Featured image of post My Monster Collection" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is what it looks like at the time of writing this. It probably took around 4 years?&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve drank from each and every can because why not right? I guess it&amp;rsquo;s more valuable if it&amp;rsquo;s still sealed? idk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/my-monster-collection/huh.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;270&#34;
	height=&#34;266&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/my-monster-collection/huh_hue7b8d425dc22ad2b98a1f253ca38ab61_65336_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/my-monster-collection/huh_hue7b8d425dc22ad2b98a1f253ca38ab61_65336_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;101&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;243px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember that one day I wen&amp;rsquo;t over to my cousin&amp;rsquo;s and he had a bunch of Red Bull cans stacked on a shelf.
That&amp;rsquo;s where I got the idea for collecting Monster cans. I thought they&amp;rsquo;d look prettier with all of the different colours.
Every friday after school I&amp;rsquo;d search for a new one at the gas station to take back home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Africa lags behind the rest of the world in pretty much everything. Shipping is insanely expensive, most things you find in grocery/convenience stores are made locally. The only one in my collection you cannot find locally is the Monster Punch. I got that from eBay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The variety here doesn&amp;rsquo;t even come &lt;strong&gt;close&lt;/strong&gt; to the variety in first world countries. It legitimately takes years for us to get new ones. To grow the collection at a faster rate I&amp;rsquo;d have to order cans from overseas but that&amp;rsquo;s pretty costly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;ll discontinue some flavours eventually. That&amp;rsquo;s when the collection would mean a lot more to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/my-monster-collection/cat.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;500&#34;
	height=&#34;500&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/my-monster-collection/cat_hue323a01c93de9b3a3c7aed31c9b26717_40757_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/my-monster-collection/cat_hue323a01c93de9b3a3c7aed31c9b26717_40757_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Software in Schools</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/software-in-schools/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/software-in-schools/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/software-in-schools/baked.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Software in Schools" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/software-in-schools/meme.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;650&#34;
	height=&#34;605&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/software-in-schools/meme_hueabf319d7ce08daedcc0202e1f831cf9_66916_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/software-in-schools/meme_hueabf319d7ce08daedcc0202e1f831cf9_66916_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;107&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;257px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rant&#34;&gt;Rant&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schools make deals with whatever company and start paying for licenses on a mass scale.
Adobe this, Microsoft this, Autodesk this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It establishes a dependent relationship between the company, the institution &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; the students.
Isn&amp;rsquo;t the whole point of going to school to make you an independent, critical-thinking member of society?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germany is pretty based and have already opened their eyes. Have a read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://thenextweb.com/news/german-schools-ban-microsoft-office-365-amid-privacy-concerns&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is a student supposed to pay an exorbitant amount of money for all of this nonsense when alternatives exist that accomplish the same goal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the devs at these companies don&amp;rsquo;t give two f*** about the consumers.
That&amp;rsquo;s not what they &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; get paid to do.
Teams monitor and collect user data like we&amp;rsquo;re in some huge guinea pig farm and make the appropriate changes to maximize revenue and get on top of their competitors.
But no look! This student has certified photoshop skills! They must be good at photo editing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any tech space &lt;strong&gt;other&lt;/strong&gt; than game development, it&amp;rsquo;s not bad. You can pretty much do whatever you want on anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently studying Game Dev.
It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;especially&lt;/strong&gt; bad in game development when you&amp;rsquo;ve got all the major engines that are proprietary like Unity and Unreal Engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nvidia will stick to proprietary drivers because Nvidia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epic Games is an absolute monster of a company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steam is proprietary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discord, the main platform for communication amongst gamers is proprietary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming peripheral companies don&amp;rsquo;t care at all about open source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All major games primarily run on Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tencent, Tencent, Tencent, Tencent, Tencent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like one long chain of poop.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But muh games! I want to play muh games!
It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to turn the blind eye for the sake of convenience.
It feels like that&amp;rsquo;s all people want nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stores like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.gog.com/about_gog&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;GOG&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://itch.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Itch.io&lt;/a&gt; are actually pretty good.
They actually care.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>An Explanation on Ocean&#39;s 47</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/steez.jpg" alt="Featured image of post An Explanation on Ocean&#39;s 47" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The man above is Courtney Jamal Dewar Jr, more commonly known as &lt;strong&gt;Capital Steez&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-capital-steez&#34;&gt;Who is Capital Steez?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital Steez &lt;strong&gt;was&lt;/strong&gt;. He was a rapper from Brooklyn, New York.
He was part of the colletive group; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pro_Era&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pro Era&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro Era or rather the Progressive Era, started out as just a group of friends in highschool, including my favourite rapper, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joey_Badass&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Joey Bada$$&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;capital-steez---apex&#34;&gt;Capital Steez - Apex&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/huISHVRUPUA&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanation&#34;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into detail about Steez&amp;rsquo;s life.
He was Joey&amp;rsquo;s best friend and unfortunately committed suicide on the 23rd of December 2012.
The numbers on date on his death &lt;code&gt;12/23/12&lt;/code&gt; add up to 47.
His last message was &amp;ldquo;THE END&amp;rdquo;.
The next album in his career was going to be called &amp;ldquo;47 Shift&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;long-live-steelo-edit&#34;&gt;Long live Steelo Edit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U-RA22CIvpk&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just simply going to explain &amp;ldquo;Ocean&amp;rsquo;s 47&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to break it up into three parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number &lt;strong&gt;47&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The word &lt;strong&gt;Ocean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Links to &lt;strong&gt;Taoism / Daoism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oceans 47&amp;rdquo; is a line from the track &amp;ldquo;Ring the Alarm&amp;rdquo; by Joey Bada$$, Meechy Darko, Kirk Knight and Nyck Caution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;#34;Death before dishonor, I die for brethren
This is a stick-up, ocean&amp;#39;s 47
Ring the alarm...&amp;#34;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-number-47&#34;&gt;The Number 47&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steez was a leader. He told his peers to do something meaningful with their lives and they followed.
The number 47 would mean nothing to Pro Era without Steez.
Steez saw the number 47 as the perfect number. It is a prime number. The number 4, represents the 4th or &lt;strong&gt;Heart&lt;/strong&gt; Chakra. The number 7, represents the 7th or &lt;strong&gt;Crown&lt;/strong&gt; Chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Steez, its the balance of the heart and mind. The balance of logical and irrational thinking. He believed that when connecting with others, you need to be sympathetic and caring while also not being completely heartless and logical. Now there&amp;rsquo;s also the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.masonic-lodge-of-education.com/47th-problem-of-euclid.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;47th problem of Euclid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, more commonly known as the &lt;strong&gt;Pythagorean&lt;/strong&gt; theorem. There&amp;rsquo;s also connections with the number 47 and the &lt;strong&gt;Swastika&lt;/strong&gt; symbol. There is &lt;strong&gt;also&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;angel numbers&amp;rdquo; and many more stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unrelated to the &lt;strong&gt;number itself&lt;/strong&gt;, is the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://faculty.fiu.edu/~harrisk/Notes/Aesthetics/Apollonian-%20Dionysian%20Dichotomy.htm&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Apollonian&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dionysian&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - directly opposing (however not antithetical) sides of Greek Culture which Friedrich Nietzsche mentioned in his work, &amp;lsquo;The Birth of Tragedy&amp;rsquo;. These dualistic and opposing &amp;lsquo;forces&amp;rsquo; are represented by the two Greek Gods; Apollo and Dionysus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apollo represents reason, rationality, calm and fortitude.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dionysus represents impulse, emotion, instinct and chaos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In simplification, Nietzsche asserted that to be content with oneself is to control the balance of these two forces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ArsS6sPhwn0&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe there is anything significant about the number and it&amp;rsquo;s various connections really. It&amp;rsquo;s about what it represents to me.
Steez&amp;rsquo;s music was highly influential and had left a mark on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do believe that there needs to be a balance between the heart and mind. The number 47 represents this to me.
I think too rationally at times; to the point where I can&amp;rsquo;t connect with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-word-ocean&#34;&gt;The Word Ocean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;lyrics&lt;/strong&gt; of the song, &amp;ldquo;Ocean&amp;rdquo; was simply a reference to the movie &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0240772/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Oceans Eleven&amp;rdquo; (2001)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, it has a different meaning. When I think of an ocean, I think of water endlessly flowing and never resting. Waves crashing. From afar, it is still. On the shore, it exerts its tremendous kinetic energy on the surrounding area. In another blog I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about my trip to Japan, but it also reminds me of the Great Wave of Hokusai for this reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great-wave-of-hokusai&#34;&gt;The Great Wave of Hokusai&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/hokusai.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;800&#34;
	height=&#34;538&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/hokusai_hu12a289ef2460acfe1fa9dc9569991029_168910_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/hokusai_hu12a289ef2460acfe1fa9dc9569991029_168910_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Great Wave Off Kanagawa | Japanese: 神奈川沖浪裏&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;148&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;356px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wave dominates the composition, emphasizing its relative size in comparison to Mount Fuji behind it and the men that are rowing for their lives.
Its destructive when energetic, yet friendly and welcoming when its not.
In a similar fashion, I feel that when people are calm and collected, they are more approachable.
More present.
Their calming and understanding essence feels soothing and even &lt;em&gt;medicinal&lt;/em&gt;.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to be this kind of person to the people I care most about, while also not being completely rational and lacking empathy in some respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, I feel the word Ocean is strongly linked to the number 47. I don&amp;rsquo;t think lyrics necessarily have to have a single-defined meaning. Its fine to interpret them in your own way as you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;taosim&#34;&gt;Taosim&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/tao.png&#34;
	width=&#34;300&#34;
	height=&#34;300&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/tao_hu2ae312aa34be84bde18807b30339ef60_66252_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/tao_hu2ae312aa34be84bde18807b30339ef60_66252_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember back in highschool, we were tasked with researching a religion of our choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t even think Taoism is a &lt;em&gt;religion&lt;/em&gt; per say. Its more like a philosophy or a way of life.
Basically it focuses on a balanced way of living life. Living life in harmony and with nature.
Importantly, in Taoism, opposites rely on each other to coexist.
This is the &lt;em&gt;only religion&lt;/em&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever come across in my life that is the most sensible and agreeable for me personally.
In this way, its linked to the dualistic behaviour of the &lt;strong&gt;ocean&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;balance of chakras&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favourite quotes from Lao Tzu, the founding philosopher of Taoism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;When people see things as beautiful, ugliness is created. ~ Lao Tzu
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-off&#34;&gt;Ending Off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoyed this short read. TLDR: I believe that having a balance in life is important.
I highly recommend to check out some of Capital Steez&amp;rsquo;s music if enjoy you &amp;lsquo;Boom-Bap&amp;rsquo; as a subgenre or just rap in general.
Peace &amp;lt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/cutecat.png&#34;
	width=&#34;480&#34;
	height=&#34;360&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/cutecat_hu7fa53c326e10933a05760b6587936164_215111_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://macawls.github.io/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/cutecat_hu7fa53c326e10933a05760b6587936164_215111_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Bangers 🎵 | Part 1</title>
        <link>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/bangers-part-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/bangers-part-1/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.github.io/blog/post/bangers-part-1/bg.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Bangers 🎵 | Part 1" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;These tracks are mostly hardstyle and techno including subgenres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1075343497&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/929893924&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1139052841&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1181250304&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1005254830&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
