<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Fluff on Macawls&#39; Blog</title>
        <link>https://macawls.dev/blog/categories/fluff/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Fluff on Macawls&#39; Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://macawls.dev/blog/categories/fluff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Mood</title>
        <link>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/mood/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/mood/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.dev/blog/post/mood/dead.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Mood" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ignorance and emotion blinds us all. The end of the world is imminent, either to artificial intelligence or global warming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology was a bad thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re driven by greed and pleasure. Humanity is a plague. We&amp;rsquo;re divided by borders, religion and other arbitrary things. We only believe in things that follow our narrative. The rich get richer. Everyone lives as a puppet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well anyways, who cares lol :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/mood/smol.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;125&#34;
	height=&#34;101&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/mood/smol_hu3cabb017450616c2ca21b5c7096f29d1_1442_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/mood/smol_hu3cabb017450616c2ca21b5c7096f29d1_1442_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;123&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;297px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Taoism and Rastafarianism</title>
        <link>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.dev/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/420.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Taoism and Rastafarianism" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I want to emphasize that what I am about to say is highly subjective and is part of my personal interpretation.
I decided to write this because I find both fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;their-origins&#34;&gt;Their Origins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For context sake, Taoism has been around for a really long time; since around the 4th century, and started in China. Rastafarianism actually started as a political movement in the 1930s in Jamaica and emerged from the &lt;strong&gt;Abrahamic&lt;/strong&gt; religions, namely Christianity and Judaism and as such, is monotheistic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also where the stark contrast between the two lies. The key word is movement. Rastafarianism never emerged solely because of religious values, but it is still essential and grounded in the movement. Taoism was purely philosophical, devoid of any politics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-definition-of-religion&#34;&gt;The definition of Religion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Religion is a difficult word to define. I personally believe both these belief systems can be defined rather as a &amp;ldquo;Way of Life&amp;rdquo; instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that when a &amp;lsquo;religion&amp;rsquo; has more strict beliefs, is unified and becomes widely institutionalized, it falls under the &amp;lsquo;religion&amp;rsquo; category. Example&amp;rsquo;s would be Christianity, Hinduism, Islam including their many respective forms and so on. However, that&amp;rsquo;s not to say places of worship for Taoism and Rastafarianism do not exist, because they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Taoism and Rastafari Culture embrace the idea of treading on your &lt;strong&gt;own&lt;/strong&gt; path to enlightenment, finding peace and content in life&amp;rsquo;s simple joys . Albeit in Rastafarianism it is much more of a collective effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/lol.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1200&#34;
	height=&#34;756&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/lol_hu6db0bf348c7f7ee1fb81ffaed16baf19_381117_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/lol_hu6db0bf348c7f7ee1fb81ffaed16baf19_381117_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;158&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;380px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nature-and-lifestyle&#34;&gt;Nature and Lifestyle&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both beliefs, there is a lot of importance placed upon living in harmony and peace with nature.
It is by far the most &lt;strong&gt;crucial&lt;/strong&gt; aspect of both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find that often in our day to day lives, we search for meaning and substance in material things.
We consume content, turn to the arts like literature and music, buy things we need or might not that serve some kind of purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end its all kinda just pointless depending on how you view it, at least it is for me.
When you stop for a second, take everything in and find peace and content by simply feeling and existing, that matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/chillcat.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;500&#34;
	height=&#34;287&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/chillcat_hu496ab323a84514f468bbad3572766ea9_35475_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/taoism-and-rastafarianism/chillcat_hu496ab323a84514f468bbad3572766ea9_35475_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;174&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;418px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How often, do you kinda just forget you have ownership of something? Or how often that one song or show you enjoyed eventually just slips out of your mind? The lessons and experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my life will never leave me. It feels much closer to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;diet&#34;&gt;Diet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rastas are primarily vegan. Their diet is called &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ital&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. They do this because it is believed that a diet free of additives, chemicals and meat is neccessary in order to stay healthy and more spiritually connected to Earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tao believe the same essentially; eating as close to natural as possible including little meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both discourage the consumption of substances such as nicotine and alcohol as well as other drugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both look down on political systems, violence and authoritarianism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to be vegetarian for around 4 months. Not because of the influences of any religion, mainly animal cruelty and because I honestly feel like humanity is a plague to the earth. Consuming meat is not a necessity by any pragmatical means.  Unfortunately I lost a significant amount of weight and it was quite difficult to have a diet different from my family&amp;rsquo;s without personal income. I plan on continuing once I am self-independent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-off&#34;&gt;Ending off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily &lt;em&gt;follow&lt;/em&gt; Taoism or Rastafarianism. There are aspects are disagree upon in both, more so in Rastafari Culture because of its misogynistic views.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Bangers 🎵 | Part 2</title>
        <link>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/bangers-part-2/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/bangers-part-2/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.dev/blog/post/bangers-part-2/monkee.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Bangers 🎵 | Part 2" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Random genres this time around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just an absolute banger this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1164496222&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beam just switches up flows like crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PmvPweUMPCE&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love the mellow vibes on this track. That synth too omg. Really catchy. A ton of big names behind production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/syNGDDMYQzg&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love singing along to this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/6XLLl1AyjD8&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My New Honda Crz (2011)</title>
        <link>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/my-new-honda-crz-2011/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/my-new-honda-crz-2011/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.dev/blog/post/my-new-honda-crz-2011/cocoa.jpg" alt="Featured image of post My New Honda Crz (2011)" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The picture looks like a terrible photoshop but things are blurred for privacy reasons.
Her name is Cocoa. No meaning behind the name, I just love calling her Cocoa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a massive fan of Japanese culture, JDM culture included. I&amp;rsquo;ll make a blog post about my previous trip to Japan soon. I make a lotta of references to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/STwMPHZNkME&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-i-like-the-car&#34;&gt;Why I like the car&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sounds kinda silly but back in the day of playing a bunch of Need for Speeds on an old PS2, I would always grab a Japanese car like the Mazda RX-8, Miata, Nissan Silva, Honda Civics etc (you get the point) and just have fun messing with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like the idea of really making something &lt;strong&gt;yours&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s also why I like linux so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s what I love about older cars, you get more bang for your buck and have so much more freedom and modularity available to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying something completely new (relatively expensive and long-term) makes me feel unhappy? Like I&amp;rsquo;m getting ripped off. I never buy anything where the emphasis is on the &lt;em&gt;brand&lt;/em&gt; and not &lt;em&gt;value for money&lt;/em&gt;. Mini-Coopers/Beats Headphones are a good examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like unique and unpopular things too. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s because I like standing out and being different or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;test-driving-the-crz&#34;&gt;Test-driving the CRZ&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It ticked all the boxes for me. The second I got in, the interior blew me away. It&amp;rsquo;s not NA, Steering wheel is on the right side for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/my-new-honda-crz-2011/interior.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;1600&#34;
	height=&#34;1200&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/my-new-honda-crz-2011/interior_hue515a5873b1eb36dc4b1e4016fe7a5cf_469057_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/my-new-honda-crz-2011/interior_hue515a5873b1eb36dc4b1e4016fe7a5cf_469057_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Interior&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 2011, it was very modern. It was comfy, a really smooth drive, pretty damn responsive in sport mode, manual transmission, great sound system, hatchback, great fuel economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only downside is that it&amp;rsquo;s a two-seater primarily but I mean, 4 people is &lt;strong&gt;possible&lt;/strong&gt;. Its just insanely uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buying-process&#34;&gt;Buying process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of getting a car was threefold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My brother need transport for university.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The car I had been driving for a year(my Mom&amp;rsquo;s) had too many problems and she did not want to sell it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unsurprisingly, &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; needed my own personal transport for the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed a decent, clean, safe and relatively new hatchback.
After test driving a bunch, my other options came down to the Renault Kwid(2020), Mini-Cooper(2012) and Honda Civic 2.2 CDTi(2011).
For &lt;strong&gt;necessity&lt;/strong&gt; sake, they were fine, checked all the boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;renault-kwid&#34;&gt;Renault Kwid&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kwid was just not fun to drive. Engine was tiny. The clutch felt really weird. I remember just lifting the boot and it felt incredibly light. On the highway, it has a tendency to sway a little bit and it just felt extremely cheap. The car was meant to be a student car, produced cheaply for the masses. It sells extremely well and is in abundance here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mini-cooper&#34;&gt;Mini Cooper&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cooper was great. It had all the bells and whistles, was fun to drive, space for everyone and the sound system was amazing.
It was pretty old though with 160K km on the clock. My only concern was repairing. Repairing a Cooper is not fun and most importantly, it&amp;rsquo;s not &lt;strong&gt;cheap&lt;/strong&gt;. After driving the CRZ, I knew my heart belonged to it but I &lt;strong&gt;might&amp;rsquo;ve&lt;/strong&gt; gone with the Cooper if the deal with the CRZ wasn&amp;rsquo;t possible. &lt;strong&gt;Maybe&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;honda-civic-22-cdti&#34;&gt;Honda Civic 2.2 CDTi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This thing was a fucking &lt;strong&gt;monster&lt;/strong&gt;. It was sooo damn responsive and stupid fast. It was so much fun to drive. Definitely the most fun car to drive out of the bunch. The problem was it was unnecessarily fast, dangerous and way too old(wasn&amp;rsquo;t looked after well). I needed a reliable daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-plans&#34;&gt;Future Plans&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll need another car eventually once I settle down, something more family oriented. Instead of replacing the CRZ I&amp;rsquo;m gonna do a K swap and Cocoa will become a project car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;K swap&amp;rdquo; means taking a Honda K series engine and putting it into something that didn&amp;rsquo;t come with a Honda K series engine. Pretty self-explanatory. The problem is, I&amp;rsquo;ll lose all the economy features but I mean you can&amp;rsquo;t really save the environment if you wanna go fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either the k20 or k24. Its in abundance here, really easy to find and relatively cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-hDt0pnHgtg&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My Monster Collection</title>
        <link>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/my-monster-collection/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/my-monster-collection/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.dev/blog/post/my-monster-collection/cans.jpg" alt="Featured image of post My Monster Collection" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is what it looks like at the time of writing this. It probably took around 4 years?&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve drank from each and every can because why not right? I guess it&amp;rsquo;s more valuable if it&amp;rsquo;s still sealed? idk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/my-monster-collection/huh.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;270&#34;
	height=&#34;266&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/my-monster-collection/huh_hue7b8d425dc22ad2b98a1f253ca38ab61_65336_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/my-monster-collection/huh_hue7b8d425dc22ad2b98a1f253ca38ab61_65336_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;101&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;243px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember that one day I wen&amp;rsquo;t over to my cousin&amp;rsquo;s and he had a bunch of Red Bull cans stacked on a shelf.
That&amp;rsquo;s where I got the idea for collecting Monster cans. I thought they&amp;rsquo;d look prettier with all of the different colours.
Every friday after school I&amp;rsquo;d search for a new one at the gas station to take back home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Africa lags behind the rest of the world in pretty much everything. Shipping is insanely expensive, most things you find in grocery/convenience stores are made locally. The only one in my collection you cannot find locally is the Monster Punch. I got that from eBay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The variety here doesn&amp;rsquo;t even come &lt;strong&gt;close&lt;/strong&gt; to the variety in first world countries. It legitimately takes years for us to get new ones. To grow the collection at a faster rate I&amp;rsquo;d have to order cans from overseas but that&amp;rsquo;s pretty costly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;ll discontinue some flavours eventually. That&amp;rsquo;s when the collection would mean a lot more to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/my-monster-collection/cat.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;500&#34;
	height=&#34;500&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/my-monster-collection/cat_hue323a01c93de9b3a3c7aed31c9b26717_40757_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/my-monster-collection/cat_hue323a01c93de9b3a3c7aed31c9b26717_40757_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Software in Schools</title>
        <link>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/software-in-schools/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/software-in-schools/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.dev/blog/post/software-in-schools/baked.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Software in Schools" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/software-in-schools/meme.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;650&#34;
	height=&#34;605&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/software-in-schools/meme_hueabf319d7ce08daedcc0202e1f831cf9_66916_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/software-in-schools/meme_hueabf319d7ce08daedcc0202e1f831cf9_66916_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;107&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;257px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rant&#34;&gt;Rant&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schools make deals with whatever company and start paying for licenses on a mass scale.
Adobe this, Microsoft this, Autodesk this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It establishes a dependent relationship between the company, the institution &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; the students.
Isn&amp;rsquo;t the whole point of going to school to make you an independent, critical-thinking member of society?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germany is pretty based and have already opened their eyes. Have a read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://thenextweb.com/news/german-schools-ban-microsoft-office-365-amid-privacy-concerns&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is a student supposed to pay an exorbitant amount of money for all of this nonsense when alternatives exist that accomplish the same goal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the devs at these companies don&amp;rsquo;t give two f*** about the consumers.
That&amp;rsquo;s not what they &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; get paid to do.
Teams monitor and collect user data like we&amp;rsquo;re in some huge guinea pig farm and make the appropriate changes to maximize revenue and get on top of their competitors.
But no look! This student has certified photoshop skills! They must be good at photo editing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any tech space &lt;strong&gt;other&lt;/strong&gt; than game development, it&amp;rsquo;s not bad. You can pretty much do whatever you want on anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently studying Game Dev.
It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;especially&lt;/strong&gt; bad in game development when you&amp;rsquo;ve got all the major engines that are proprietary like Unity and Unreal Engine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nvidia will stick to proprietary drivers because Nvidia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Epic Games is an absolute monster of a company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steam is proprietary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discord, the main platform for communication amongst gamers is proprietary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaming peripheral companies don&amp;rsquo;t care at all about open source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All major games primarily run on Windows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tencent, Tencent, Tencent, Tencent, Tencent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like one long chain of poop.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But muh games! I want to play muh games!
It&amp;rsquo;s so easy to turn the blind eye for the sake of convenience.
It feels like that&amp;rsquo;s all people want nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stores like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.gog.com/about_gog&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;GOG&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://itch.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Itch.io&lt;/a&gt; are actually pretty good.
They actually care.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>An Explanation on Ocean&#39;s 47</title>
        <link>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.dev/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/steez.jpg" alt="Featured image of post An Explanation on Ocean&#39;s 47" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The man above is Courtney Jamal Dewar Jr, more commonly known as &lt;strong&gt;Capital Steez&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-capital-steez&#34;&gt;Who is Capital Steez?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital Steez &lt;strong&gt;was&lt;/strong&gt;. He was a rapper from Brooklyn, New York.
He was part of the colletive group; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pro_Era&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pro Era&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro Era or rather the Progressive Era, started out as just a group of friends in highschool, including my favourite rapper, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joey_Badass&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Joey Bada$$&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;capital-steez---apex&#34;&gt;Capital Steez - Apex&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/huISHVRUPUA&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;explanation&#34;&gt;Explanation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into detail about Steez&amp;rsquo;s life.
He was Joey&amp;rsquo;s best friend and unfortunately committed suicide on the 23rd of December 2012.
The numbers on date on his death &lt;code&gt;12/23/12&lt;/code&gt; add up to 47.
His last message was &amp;ldquo;THE END&amp;rdquo;.
The next album in his career was going to be called &amp;ldquo;47 Shift&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;long-live-steelo-edit&#34;&gt;Long live Steelo Edit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/U-RA22CIvpk&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m just simply going to explain &amp;ldquo;Ocean&amp;rsquo;s 47&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to break it up into three parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number &lt;strong&gt;47&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The word &lt;strong&gt;Ocean&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Links to &lt;strong&gt;Taoism / Daoism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oceans 47&amp;rdquo; is a line from the track &amp;ldquo;Ring the Alarm&amp;rdquo; by Joey Bada$$, Meechy Darko, Kirk Knight and Nyck Caution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Death before dishonor, I die for brethren
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;This is a stick-up, ocean&amp;#39;s 47
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Ring the alarm...&amp;#34;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-number-47&#34;&gt;The Number 47&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steez was a leader. He told his peers to do something meaningful with their lives and they followed.
The number 47 would mean nothing to Pro Era without Steez.
Steez saw the number 47 as the perfect number. It is a prime number. The number 4, represents the 4th or &lt;strong&gt;Heart&lt;/strong&gt; Chakra. The number 7, represents the 7th or &lt;strong&gt;Crown&lt;/strong&gt; Chakra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Steez, its the balance of the heart and mind. The balance of logical and irrational thinking. He believed that when connecting with others, you need to be sympathetic and caring while also not being completely heartless and logical. Now there&amp;rsquo;s also the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.masonic-lodge-of-education.com/47th-problem-of-euclid.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;47th problem of Euclid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, more commonly known as the &lt;strong&gt;Pythagorean&lt;/strong&gt; theorem. There&amp;rsquo;s also connections with the number 47 and the &lt;strong&gt;Swastika&lt;/strong&gt; symbol. There is &lt;strong&gt;also&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ldquo;angel numbers&amp;rdquo; and many more stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unrelated to the &lt;strong&gt;number itself&lt;/strong&gt;, is the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://faculty.fiu.edu/~harrisk/Notes/Aesthetics/Apollonian-%20Dionysian%20Dichotomy.htm&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Apollonian&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Dionysian&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - directly opposing (however not antithetical) sides of Greek Culture which Friedrich Nietzsche mentioned in his work, &amp;lsquo;The Birth of Tragedy&amp;rsquo;. These dualistic and opposing &amp;lsquo;forces&amp;rsquo; are represented by the two Greek Gods; Apollo and Dionysus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apollo represents reason, rationality, calm and fortitude.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dionysus represents impulse, emotion, instinct and chaos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In simplification, Nietzsche asserted that to be content with oneself is to control the balance of these two forces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;video-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;iframe loading=&#34;lazy&#34; 
            src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ArsS6sPhwn0&#34; 
            allowfullscreen 
            title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;
    &gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe there is anything significant about the number and it&amp;rsquo;s various connections really. It&amp;rsquo;s about what it represents to me.
Steez&amp;rsquo;s music was highly influential and had left a mark on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do believe that there needs to be a balance between the heart and mind. The number 47 represents this to me.
I think too rationally at times; to the point where I can&amp;rsquo;t connect with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-word-ocean&#34;&gt;The Word Ocean&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;lyrics&lt;/strong&gt; of the song, &amp;ldquo;Ocean&amp;rdquo; was simply a reference to the movie &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0240772/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;Oceans Eleven&amp;rdquo; (2001)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, it has a different meaning. When I think of an ocean, I think of water endlessly flowing and never resting. Waves crashing. From afar, it is still. On the shore, it exerts its tremendous kinetic energy on the surrounding area. In another blog I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about my trip to Japan, but it also reminds me of the Great Wave of Hokusai for this reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-great-wave-of-hokusai&#34;&gt;The Great Wave of Hokusai&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/hokusai.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;800&#34;
	height=&#34;538&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/hokusai_hu12a289ef2460acfe1fa9dc9569991029_168910_480x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 480w, https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/hokusai_hu12a289ef2460acfe1fa9dc9569991029_168910_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Great Wave Off Kanagawa | Japanese: 神奈川沖浪裏&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;148&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;356px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The wave dominates the composition, emphasizing its relative size in comparison to Mount Fuji behind it and the men that are rowing for their lives.
Its destructive when energetic, yet friendly and welcoming when its not.
In a similar fashion, I feel that when people are calm and collected, they are more approachable.
More present.
Their calming and understanding essence feels soothing and even &lt;em&gt;medicinal&lt;/em&gt;.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to be this kind of person to the people I care most about, while also not being completely rational and lacking empathy in some respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, I feel the word Ocean is strongly linked to the number 47. I don&amp;rsquo;t think lyrics necessarily have to have a single-defined meaning. Its fine to interpret them in your own way as you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;taosim&#34;&gt;Taosim&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/tao.png&#34;
	width=&#34;300&#34;
	height=&#34;300&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/tao_hu2ae312aa34be84bde18807b30339ef60_66252_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/tao_hu2ae312aa34be84bde18807b30339ef60_66252_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;100&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;240px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember back in highschool, we were tasked with researching a religion of our choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t even think Taoism is a &lt;em&gt;religion&lt;/em&gt; per say. Its more like a philosophy or a way of life.
Basically it focuses on a balanced way of living life. Living life in harmony and with nature.
Importantly, in Taoism, opposites rely on each other to coexist.
This is the &lt;em&gt;only religion&lt;/em&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;ve ever come across in my life that is the most sensible and agreeable for me personally.
In this way, its linked to the dualistic behaviour of the &lt;strong&gt;ocean&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;balance of chakras&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favourite quotes from Lao Tzu, the founding philosopher of Taoism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;When people see things as beautiful, ugliness is created. ~ Lao Tzu
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ending-off&#34;&gt;Ending Off&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoyed this short read. TLDR: I believe that having a balance in life is important.
I highly recommend to check out some of Capital Steez&amp;rsquo;s music if enjoy you &amp;lsquo;Boom-Bap&amp;rsquo; as a subgenre or just rap in general.
Peace &amp;lt;3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/cutecat.png&#34;
	width=&#34;480&#34;
	height=&#34;360&#34;
	srcset=&#34;https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/cutecat_hu7fa53c326e10933a05760b6587936164_215111_480x0_resize_box_3.png 480w, https://macawls.dev/blog/blog/post/an-explanation-on-oceans-47/cutecat_hu7fa53c326e10933a05760b6587936164_215111_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w&#34;
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Bangers 🎵 | Part 1</title>
        <link>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/bangers-part-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://macawls.dev/blog/post/bangers-part-1/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://macawls.dev/blog/post/bangers-part-1/bg.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Bangers 🎵 | Part 1" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;These tracks are mostly hardstyle and techno including subgenres.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1075343497&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/929893924&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1139052841&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1181250304&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; 
height=&#34;166&#34; 
scrolling=&#34;no&#34; 
frameborder=&#34;no&#34; 
allow=&#34;autoplay&#34; 
src=&#34;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1005254830&amp;color=%231c1511&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&#34;
&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
